<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE html>
<html lang="no">
  <head>
    <title>Forskrift om endringer i forskrift om tiltak vedr. Ukrainas integritet mv.</title>
    <base href="https://lovdata.no/"/>
  </head>
  <body>
    <header class="documentHeader" id="hode">
      <dl class="data-document-key-info">
        <dt class="legacyID">Datokode</dt>
        <dd class="legacyID">FOR-2014-03-26-350</dd>
        <dt class="dokid">DokumentID</dt>
        <dd class="dokid">LTI/forskrift/2014-03-26-350</dd>
        <dt class="ministry">Departement</dt>
        <dd class="ministry">
          <ul>
            <li>Utenriksdepartementet</li>
          </ul>
        </dd>
        <dt class="publishedIn">Publisert i</dt>
        <dd class="publishedIn">I 2014 hefte 4 s 587</dd>
        <dt class="dateInForce">I kraft fra</dt>
        <dd class="dateInForce">2014-03-26</dd>
        <dt class="changesToDocuments">Endrer</dt>
        <dd class="changesToDocuments">
          <ul>
            <li>forskrift/2014-03-21-301</li>
          </ul>
        </dd>
        <dt class="appliesTo">Gjelder for</dt>
        <dd class="appliesTo">Norge</dd>
        <dt class="basedOn">Hjemmel</dt>
        <dd class="basedOn">
          <ul>
            <li>forskrift/2014-03-21-301/&#xA7;13</li>
            <li>lov/2001-04-27-14</li>
          </ul>
        </dd>
        <dt class="dateOfPublication">Kunngjort</dt>
        <dd class="dateOfPublication">2014-04-01 15:45</dd>
        <dt class="journalNumber">Journalnummer</dt>
        <dd class="journalNumber">2014-0246</dd>
        <dt class="titleShort">Korttittel</dt>
        <dd class="titleShort">Endr. i forskrift om tiltak vedr&#xF8;rende Ukrainas</dd>
        <dt class="title">Tittel</dt>
        <dd class="title">Forskrift om endringer i forskrift om tiltak vedr. Ukrainas integritet mv.</dd>
        <dt class="miscInformation">Annet om dokumentet</dt>
        <dd class="miscInformation"><strong>Hjemmel:</strong> Fastsatt av Utenriksdepartementet 26. mars 2014 med hjemmel i forskrift 21. mars 2014 nr. 301 om restriktive tiltak vedr&#xF8;rende handlinger som undergraver eller truer Ukrainas territorielle integritet, suverenitet og uavhengighet &#xA7; 13.</dd>
        <dt class="refid">RefID</dt>
        <dd class="refid">forskrift/2014-03-26-350</dd>
        <dt class="table-of-contents">Innhold</dt>
        <dd class="table-of-contents">
          <ul class="tocTopUl">
            <li>Forskrift om endringer i forskrift om tiltak vedr. Ukrainas integritet mv.<ul class="tocSubUl"><li>I</li><li>II</li></ul></li>
          </ul>
        </dd>
      </dl>
    </header>
    <main class="documentBody" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2014-03-26-350" id="dokument">
      <h1>Forskrift om endringer i forskrift om tiltak vedr. Ukrainas integritet mv.</h1>
      <section class="section" data-name="kapI" id="kapittel-1" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2014-03-26-350/KAPITTEL_1">
        <h2 data-text-align="center">I</h2>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-1">I forskrift 21. mars 2014 nr. 301 om restriktive tiltak vedr&#xF8;rende handlinger som undergraver eller truer Ukrainas territorielle integritet, suverenitet og uavhengighet gj&#xF8;res f&#xF8;lgende endring:</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Gjeldende vedlegg I erstattes av vedlagte vedlegg I.</article>
        <span class="futuretitle" id="kapittel-1-foresl&#xE5;ttittel-1">Vedlegg I. Liste over personer</span>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-2">Informasjon vedr&#xF8;rende samtlige listef&#xF8;rte personer er rubrisert slik:<ul class="defaultList"><li data-li-identifier="-" data-name="-"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-1-ledd-2-punkt-1"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-2-punkt-1-ledd-1">Navn</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="-" data-name="-"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-1-ledd-2-punkt-2"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-2-punkt-2-ledd-1">Identifiserende informasjon og f&#xF8;dselsdato der tilgjengelig</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="-" data-name="-"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-1-ledd-2-punkt-3"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-2-punkt-3-ledd-1">Grunnlag</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="-" data-name="-"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-1-ledd-2-punkt-4"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-2-punkt-4-ledd-1">Dato for EUs listef&#xF8;ring.</article></article></li></ul></article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>1. Sergey Valeryevich Aksyonov</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 26.11.1972</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Aksyonov was elected &#xAB;Prime Minister of Crimea&#xBB; in the Crimean Verkhovna Rada on 27 February 2014 in the presence of pro-Russian gunmen. His &#xAB;election&#xBB; was decreed unconstitutional by Oleksandr Turchynov on 1 March. He actively lobbied for the &#xAB;referendum&#xBB; of 16 March 2014.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>2. Vladimir Andreevich Konstantinov</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 19.03.1967</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">As speaker of the Supreme Council of the Autonomous Republic of Crimea, Konstantinov played a relevant role in the decisions taken by the Verkhovna Rada concerning the &#xAB;referendum&#xBB; against territorial integrity of Ukraine and called on voters to cast votes in favour of Crimean Independence.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>3. Rustam Ilmirovich Temirgaliev</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 15.08.1976</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">As Deputy Chairman of the Council of Ministers of Crimea, Temirgaliev played a relevant role in the decisions taken by the Verkhovna Rada concerning the &#xAB;referendum&#xBB; against territorial integrity of Ukraine. He lobbied actively for integration of Crimea into the Russian Federation.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>4. Deniz Valentinovich Berezovskiy</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 15.07.1974</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Berezovskiy was appointed commander of the Ukrainian Navy on 1 March 2014 and swore an oath to the Crimean armed force, thereby breaking his oath. The Prosecutor-General's Office of Ukraine launched an investigation against him for high treason.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>5. Aleksei Mikhailovich Chaliy</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 13.06.1961</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Chaliy became &#xAB;Mayor of Sevastopol&#xBB; by popular acclamation on 23 February 2014 and accepted this &#xAB;vote&#xBB;. He actively campaigned for Sevastopol to become a separate entity of the Russian Federation following a referendum on 16 March 2014.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>6. Pyotr Anatoliyovych Zima</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Zima was appointed as the new head of the Crimean Security Service (SBU) on 3 March 2014 by &#xAB;Prime Minister&#xBB; Aksyonov and accepted this appointment. He has given relevant information including a database to the Russian Intelligence Service (SBU). This included information on Euro- Maidan activists and human rights defenders of Crimea. He played a relevant role in preventing Ukraine's authorities from controlling the territory of Crimea. On 11 March 2014 the formation of an independent Security Service of Crimea has been proclaimed by former SBU officers of Crimea.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>7. Yuriy Zherebtsov</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Counsellor of the Speaker of the Verkhovna Rada of Crimea, one of the leading organizers of the 16 March 2014 &#xAB;referendum&#xBB; against Ukraine's territorial integrity.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>8. Sergey Pavlovych Tsekov</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 28.03.1953</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Vice Speaker of the Verkhovna Rada; Tsekov initiated together with Sergey Aksyonov the unlawful dismissal of the government of the Autonomous Republic of Crimea (ARC). He drew into this endeavour Vladimir Konstantinov, threatening him with his dismissal. He publicly recognized that the MPs from Crimea were the initiators of inviting Russian soldiers to take over Verkhovna Rada of Crimea. He was one of the first Crimean Leaders to ask in public for annexation of Crimea to Russia.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>9. Ozerov, Viktor Alekseevich</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 5.1.1958 in Abakan, Khakassia</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Chairman of the Security and Defense Committee of the Federation Council of the Russian Federation. On 1 March 2014 Ozerov, on behalf of the Security and Defense Committee of the Federation Council, publicly supported in the Federation Council the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>10. Dzhabarov, Vladimir Michailovich</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 29.9.1952</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">First Deputy-Chairman of the International Affairs Committee of the Federation Council of the Russian Federation. On 1 March 2014 Dzhabarov, on behalf of the International Affairs Committee of the Federation Council, publicly supported in the Federation Council the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>11. Klishas, Andrei Aleksandrovich</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 9.11.1972 in Sverdlovsk</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Chairman of the Committee on Constitutional Law of the Federation Council of the Russian Federation. On 1 March 2014 Klishas publicly supported in the Federation Council the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine. In public statements Klishas sought to justify a Russian military intervention in Ukraine by claiming that &#xAB;the Ukrainian President supports the appeal of the Crimean authorities to the President of the Russian Federation on landing an all-encompassing assistance in defense of the citizens of Crimea&#xBB;.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>12. Ryzhkov, Nikolai Ivanovich</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 28.9.1929 in Duleevka, Donetsk region, Ukrainian SSR</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Member of the Committee for federal issues, regional politics and the North of the Federation Council of the Russian Federation. On 1 March 2014 Ryzhkov publicly supported in the Federation Council the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>13. Bushmin, Evgeni Viktorovich</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 4.10.1958 in Lopatino, Sergachiisky region, RSFSR</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Deputy Speaker of the Federation Council of the Russian Federation. On 1 March 2014 Bushmin publicly supported in the Federation Council the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>14. Totoonov, Aleksandr Borisovich</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 3.3.1957 in Ordzhonikidze, North Ossetia</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Member of the Committee on culture, science, and information of the Federation Council of the Russian Federation. On 1 March 2014 Totoonov publicly supported in the Federation Council the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>15. Panteleev, Oleg Evgenevich</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 21.7.1952 in Zhitnikovskoe, Kurgan region</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">First Deputy Chairman of the Committee on Parliamentary Issues. On 1 March 2014 Panteleev publicly supported in the Federation Council the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>16. Mironov, Sergei Mikhailovich</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 14.2.1953 in Pushkin, Leningrad region</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Member of the Council of the State Duma; Leader of Fair Russia faction in the Duma of the Russian Federation. Initiator of the bill allowing Russian Federation to admit in its composition, under the pretext of protection of Russian citizens, territories of a foreign country without a consent of that country or of an international treaty.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>17. Zheleznyak, Sergei Vladimirovich</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 30.7.1970 in St Petersburg (former Leningrad)</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Deputy Speaker of the State Duma of the Russian Federation. Actively supporting use of Russian Armed Forces in Ukraine and annexation of Crimea. He led personally the demonstration in support of the use of Russian Armed Forces in Ukraine.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>18. Slutski, Leonid Eduardovich</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 4.01.1968 in Moscow</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Chairman of the Commonwealth of Independent States (CIS) Committee of the State Duma of the Russian Federation (member of the LDPR). Actively supporting use of Russian Armed Forces in Ukraine and annexation of Crimea.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>19. Vitko, Aleksandr Viktorovich</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 13.9.1961 in Vitebsk (Belarusian SSR)</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Commander of the Black Sea Fleet, Vice-Admiral. Responsible for commanding Russian forces that have occupied Ukrainian sovereign territory.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>20. Sidorov, Anatoliy Alekseevich</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Commander, Russia's Western Military District, units of which are deployed in Crimea. Commander of Russia's Western Military District, units of which are deployed in Crimea. He is responsible for part of the Russian military presence in Crimea which is undermining the sovereignty of the Ukraine and assisted the Crimean authorities in preventing public demonstrations against moves towards a referendum and incorporation into Russia.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>21. Galkin, Aleksandr</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Russia's Southern Military District, forces of which are in Crimea; the Black Sea Fleet comes under Galkin's command; much of the force movement into Crimea has come through the Southern Military District. Commander of Russia's Southern Military District (&#xAB;SMD&#xBB;). SMD forces are deployed in Crimea. He is responsible for part of the Russian military presence in Crimea which is undermining the sovereignty of the Ukraine and assisted the Crimean authorities in preventing public demonstrations against moves towards a referendum and incorporation into Russia. Additionally the Black Sea Fleet falls within the District's control.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">17.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>22. Rogozin, Dmitry Olegovich</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 21.12.1963; in Moscow</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Deputy Prime Minister of the Russian Federation. Publicly called for the annexation of Crimea.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">21.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>23. Glazyev, Sergey</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 1.1.1961, Zaporozhye, (Ukrainian SSR)</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Adviser to the President of the Russian Federation. Publicly called for the annexation of Crimea.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">21.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>24. Matviyenko, Valentina Ivanova</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 7.4.1949, Shepetovka, Khmelnitskyi oblast (Ukrainian SSR)</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Speaker of the Federation Council. On 1 March 2014, publicly supported in the Federation Council the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">21.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>25. Naryshkin, Sergei Evgenevich</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 27.10.1954, St Petersburg (former Leningrad)</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Speaker of the State Duma. Publicly supported the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine. Publicly supported the Russia-Crimea reunification treaty and the related federal constitutional law.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">21.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>26. Kiselyov, Dmitry Konstantinovich</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 26.4.1954</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Appointed by Presidential Decree on 9 December 2013 Head of the Russian Federal State news agency &#xAB;Rossiya Segodnya&#xBB;. Central figure of the government propaganda supporting the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">21.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>27. Nosatov, Alexander Mihailovich</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 27.3.1963 Sevastopol, (Ukrainian SSR)</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Deputy-Commander of the Black Sea Fleet, Rear-Admiral. Responsible for commanding Russian forces that have occupied Ukrainian sovereign territory.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">21.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>28. Kulikov, Valery Vladimirovich</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 1.9.1956, Zaporozhye, (Ukrainian SSR)</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Deputy-Commander of the Black Sea Fleet, Rear Admiral. Responsible for commanding Russian forces that have occupied Ukrainian sovereign territory.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">21.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>29. Surkov, Vladislav Yurievich</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">D.o.b. 21.9.1964, Solntsevo, Lipetsk</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Aide to the President of the Russian Federation. He was an organiser of the process in Crimea by which local Crimean communities were mobilised to stage actions undermining the Ukrainian authorities in Crimea.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">21.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>30. Mikhail Malyshev</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Chair of the Crimea Electoral Commission</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Responsible for administering the Crimean referendum. Responsible under the Russian system for signing referendum results.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">21.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>31. Valery Medvedev</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Chair of Sevastopol Electoral Commission</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Responsible for administering the Crimean referendum. Responsible under the Russian system for signing referendum results.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">21.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>32. Lt. Gen. Igor Turchenyuk</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Commander of the Russian forces in Crimea</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">The de-facto Commander of Russian troops deployed on the ground in Crimea (whom Russia continues to refer to officially as &#xAB;local self-defence militias&#xBB;).</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">21.3.2014</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">
          <i>33. Elena Borisovna Mizulina</i>
        </article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Deputy in the State Duma</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Originator and co-sponsor of recent legislative proposals in Russia that would have allowed regions of other countries to join Russia without their central authorities' prior agreement.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">21.3.2014</article>
      </section>
      <section class="section" data-name="kapII" id="kapittel-2" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2014-03-26-350/KAPITTEL_2">
        <h2 data-text-align="center">II</h2>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-2-ledd-1">Endringen trer i kraft straks.</article>
      </section>
    </main>
  </body>
</html>
