<!DOCTYPE html><html lang="no"><head><title>School Regulations applicable to the Pilot Flight Academy AS</title><base href="https://lovdata.no/" /></head><body><header class="documentHeader" id="hode"><dl class="data-document-key-info"><dt class="legacyID">Datokode</dt><dd class="legacyID">FOR-2017-09-12-1742</dd><dt class="dokid">DokumentID</dt><dd class="dokid">LTI/forskrift/2017-09-12-1742</dd><dt class="ministry">Departement</dt><dd class="ministry"><ul><li>Kunnskapsdepartementet</li></ul></dd><dt class="dateInForce">I kraft fra</dt><dd class="dateInForce">2017-09-12</dd><dt class="appliesTo">Gjelder for</dt><dd class="appliesTo">Norge</dd><dt class="basedOn">Hjemmel</dt><dd class="basedOn"><ul><li>lov/2003-06-20-56/§4</li><li>lov/2003-06-20-56/§5</li><li>lov/2003-06-20-56/§6</li><li>lov/2003-06-20-56/§7</li><li>lov/2003-06-20-56/§8</li><li>lov/2003-06-20-56/§9</li><li>lov/2003-06-20-56/§10</li><li>lov/2003-06-20-56/§13</li><li>forskrift/2017-03-17-334</li></ul></dd><dt class="dateOfPublication">Kunngjort</dt><dd class="dateOfPublication">2017-11-09 14:35</dd><dt class="journalNumber">Journalnummer</dt><dd class="journalNumber">2017-1147</dd><dt class="titleShort">Korttittel</dt><dd class="titleShort">School Regulations applicable to the Pilot Flight Academy AS</dd><dt class="title">Tittel</dt><dd class="title">School Regulations applicable to the Pilot Flight Academy AS</dd><dt class="miscInformation">Annet om dokumentet</dt><dd class="miscInformation"><strong>Hjemmel:</strong> Fastsatt av styret i Pilot Flight Academy AS 12. september 2017 med hjemmel i lov 20. juni 2003 nr. 56 om fagskoleutdanning (fagskoleloven) § 4, § 5, § 6, § 7, § 8, § 9, § 10 og § 13 og forskrift 17. mars 2017 nr. 334 om fagskoleutdanning.</dd><dt class="refid">RefID</dt><dd class="refid">forskrift/2017-09-12-1742</dd><dt class="table-of-contents">Innhold</dt><dd class="table-of-contents"><ul class="tocTopUl"><li>School Regulations applicable to the Pilot Flight Academy AS<ul class="tocSubUl"><li>1. Rights and duties</li><li>2. Educational programs, admission requirements etc.</li><li>3. Exemption for parts of the education<ul class="tocSubUl"><li>General provisions</li></ul></li><li>4. Internal provisions at the PFA</li><li>5. The duties of the training provider</li><li>6. The content of the education and diploma. Law of vocational school of education (lov om fagskoleutdanning) § 5</li><li>7. Complaint about formal errors at the exam. Law of vocational school of education (lov om fagskoleutdanning) § 7</li><li>8. Entitled to explanation. Complaint about the sanction. Law of vocational school of education (lov om fagskoleutdanning) § 8</li><li>9. Cancellation of the exam. Law of vocational school of education (lov om fagskoleutdanning) § 9</li><li>10. Exclusion and expulsion. Law of vocational school of education (lov om fagskoleutdanning) § 10</li><li>11. Assessment of suitability. Law of vocational school of education (lov om fagskoleutdanning) § 11</li><li>12. Appeals and appeal bodies. Law of vocational school of education (lov om fagskoleutdanningning) § 13</li><li>The entry into force of these provisions</li></ul></li></ul></dd></dl></header><main class="documentBody" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2017-09-12-1742" id="dokument"><h1>School Regulations applicable to the Pilot Flight Academy AS</h1><article class="legalP" id="ledd-1">These regulations state the rights and duties for the students attending the training courses of the Pilot Flight Academy AS, hereafter named the PFA. The regulations are published on the website of the PFA, and the students are informed about the regulations at the start of the studies.</article><section class="section" data-name="kap1" id="kapittel-1" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2017-09-12-1742/KAPITTEL_1"><h2>1. Rights and duties</h2><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-1-punkt-1"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">1.1</span><span class="miscHeadline"><i>Rights</i></span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-punkt-1-ledd-1">The students at the PFA are entitled to receive the training, support and guidance which are in accordance with the Norwegian Law of vocational school of education. (lov om fagskoleutdanning)</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-1-punkt-2"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">1.2</span><span class="miscHeadline"><i>Duties</i></span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-punkt-2-ledd-1">The students are obliged to familiarize themselves with and to comply with regulations, instructions and provisions laid down at the PFA.</article></article></section><section class="section" data-name="kap2" id="kapittel-2" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2017-09-12-1742/KAPITTEL_2"><h2>2. Educational programs, admission requirements etc.</h2><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-2-ledd-1">Information and guidance about the PFA's educational and training programs, application process, costs and financing etc. appear on the PFA's website; www.pilot.no</article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-2-punkt-1"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">2.1.</span><span class="miscHeadline"><i>Admission criteria for the pilot studies at the PFA</i></span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-2-punkt-1-ledd-1">The applicant must meet the requirement for the education he or she is applying for.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-2-punkt-1-ledd-2">The requirements appear on the PFA's website; www.pilot.no</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-2-punkt-1-ledd-3">In addition to the above stated criteria, foreign applicants from non-EU countries must have a valid student visa for Norway, ref. www.udi.no</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-2-punkt-1-ledd-4">Employers within the aviation industry, may require a police certificate from job applicants.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-2-punkt-2"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">2.2</span><span class="miscHeadline"><i>Complaint about admission to the PFA</i></span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-2-punkt-2-ledd-1">Decisions about admission to the school shall be in accordance with the Law of Administration (forvaltningsloven) § 24 and can be appealed under the provisions of the Law of vocational school of education (lov om fagskoleutdanning) § 13 and the Law of Administration § 28. The deadline for appeals is three weeks from the time that the complainant was informed of the decision, ref. the Law of Administration (forvaltningsloven) § 29. The applicant may request an explanation for any refusal of the application. The appellate is the appeal board appointed by the board of PFA.</article></article></section><section class="section" data-name="kap3" id="kapittel-3" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2017-09-12-1742/KAPITTEL_3"><h2>3. Exemption for parts of the education</h2><section class="section" id="kapittel-3-kapittel-1" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2017-09-12-1742/KAPITTEL_3-1"><h3>General provisions</h3><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-3-kapittel-1-punkt-1"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">3.1.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-kapittel-1-punkt-1-ledd-1">An application for exemption must be supported by certificates, copyright evidence, logbooks or other documentation accepted by the Norwegian Civil Aviation Authority, (CAA-N).</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-3-kapittel-1-punkt-2"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">3.2.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-kapittel-1-punkt-2-ledd-1">A student may only apply for exemption for parts of the education after he or she has been offered a study place.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-3-kapittel-1-punkt-3"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">3.3.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-kapittel-1-punkt-3-ledd-1">An exemption application is to be decided by the school's Head of Training.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-3-kapittel-1-punkt-4"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">3.4.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-kapittel-1-punkt-4-ledd-1">Applicants may contest the decisions of exemption under the same rules as described in paragraph 2.2 above.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-3-kapittel-1-punkt-5"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">3.5.</span><span class="miscHeadline"><i>Rules regarding Modular and Integrated flight crew education</i></span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-kapittel-1-punkt-5-ledd-1">Students having achieved equivalent training may, in accordance with the rules of these present regulations, apply for exemption from parts of the training.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-3-kapittel-1-punkt-6"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">3.6.</span><span class="miscHeadline"><i>Rules regarding MPL(A) Integrated flight crew training</i></span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-kapittel-1-punkt-6-ledd-1">Students for MPL(A) may only gain access to the course as ab-initio- students.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-3-kapittel-1-punkt-7"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">3.7.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-kapittel-1-punkt-7-ledd-1">If during the course the student wishes to transfer from another flight school to the PFA, he or she must apply to the CAA-N for a formal assessment regarding any extra training hours for the student which should be carried out at the PFA.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-3-kapittel-1-punkt-8"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">3.8.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-kapittel-1-punkt-8-ledd-1">Before the student is allowed to start the course, the school has to make sure that he or she has sufficient knowledge to understand the theoretical and practical part of the training.</article></article></section></section><section class="section" data-name="kap4" id="kapittel-4" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2017-09-12-1742/KAPITTEL_4"><h2>4. Internal provisions at the PFA</h2><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-4-punkt-1"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">4.1.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-punkt-1-ledd-1">During the course of training the student must follow and comply with the regulations and rules issued by the PFA for the operation of the school.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-punkt-1-ledd-2">The student must familiarize her/himself with the course descriptions and comply with the following requirements. The student must attend training as specified in the course schedule and check for updates as circulated by the PFA.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-punkt-1-ledd-3">If a student wishes to terminate the training before it is completed, the Head of Training must be notified in writing.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-4-punkt-2"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">4.2.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-punkt-2-ledd-1">If damage to equipment, buildings, inventory etc. owned by or used by the PFA occurs, the management of the school must be notified by the person responsible for the damage, or by others who observe or discover the damage.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-punkt-2-ledd-2">A student who is responsible for damage caused either by intentional or negligent appearance or negligent treatment of equipment, inventory etc. may be held financially responsible for the damage.</article></article></section><section class="section" data-name="kap5" id="kapittel-5" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2017-09-12-1742/KAPITTEL_5"><h2>5. The duties of the training provider</h2><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-5-punkt-1"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">5.1.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-5-punkt-1-ledd-1">The training provider (PFA) is obligated to comply with the provisions of § 4 and § 4a of the Law of vocational school of education (lov om fagskoleutdanning).</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-5-punkt-1-ledd-2">The provisions of these articles include measures to create and ensure a motivating, inspiring and competent environment and basis for the implementation of the educational opportunities offered by the provider.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-5-punkt-1-ledd-3">The provisions include the creation and maintenance of an environment of good and solid cooperation between the students and the management of the school.</article></article></section><section class="section" data-name="kap6" id="kapittel-6" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2017-09-12-1742/KAPITTEL_6"><h2>6. The content of the education and diploma. Law of vocational school of education (lov om fagskoleutdanning) § 5</h2><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-ledd-1">The provider is required to have a plan regarding the structure and content of the education, and methods of implementation of the education.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-ledd-2">The school issues diplomas upon completion of the courses. NOKUT may issue provision regarding the content of the diplomas.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-ledd-3">Students who do not complete the education may request a statement that shows the grades of passing exams, tests and other assessments completed.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-ledd-4">The exams of Modular and Integrated flight crew education and Integrated flight crew training MPL(A) must comply with the provisions and procedures of EASA PART-FCL.</article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-6-punkt-1"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">6.1.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-punkt-1-ledd-1">The objective of Modular and Integrated flight crew education is to train students to the required skill level for operating as co-pilot on a multi-pilot and multi-engine aeroplane used for commercial operations, and for the purpose of having a JAR-FCL CPL(A) IR ME license.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-6-punkt-2"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">6.2.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-punkt-2-ledd-1">The objective of Integrated flight crew training MPL(A) is to train students to the required skill level for operating as co-pilot on a multi-engine turbine powered transportation aircraft registered for a minimum crew of two pilots under VFR and IFR, and for the purpose of having a JAR-FCL MPL(A) License.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-6-punkt-3"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">6.3.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-punkt-3-ledd-1">A student who fails to pass CAA-N's theoretical or practical tests or is incapable of completing the education may appeal to the CAA-N for a theoretical exam and a skill test for a less comprehensive license, and, if applicable, for an instrument rating.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-6-punkt-4"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">6.4.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-punkt-4-ledd-1">A student planning to obtain a private pilot license should demonstrate to the CAA-N the theoretical skills on a level equivalent to the privileges granted the holder of a PPL(A).</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-6-punkt-5"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">6.5.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-punkt-5-ledd-1">A student must pass the theoretical exams and skilltests for commercial pilot license to meet the requirements of the level of theoretical and practical skills required for the issuance of CPL(A), including class- or type-approval for the aeroplane(s) used during the test(s), and instrumental approval for multi-engine aeroplanes.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-6-punkt-6"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">6.6.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-punkt-6-ledd-1">A student must pass the theoretical exams and the demonstration of skills to an acceptable level for obtaining a pilot license to meet the requirements of the level of theoretical and practical skills required for the issuance of MPL(A), including type-approval for the aeroplane(s) used during the test(s) and instrumental approval limited to turbine powered transportation aircraft registered for a minimum crew of two pilots.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-6-punkt-7"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">6.7.</span><span class="miscHeadline"><i>Registration for the exam</i></span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-punkt-7-ledd-1">Students who have passed the school's theoretical tests (Progress tests) and the school's practical checks (progress checks), within four attempts, can be registered for the exam and the practical test. This opportunity applies to students who have participated in more than 90&#xa0;% of the tuition within each individual theoretical subject, and as well as having completed all practical flight training.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-punkt-7-ledd-2">Apart from what is stated above, all registrations for the exam are regulated by the guidelines adopted by CAA-N.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-6-punkt-8"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">6.8.</span><span class="miscHeadline"><i>The theory exam</i></span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-punkt-8-ledd-1">A student working to obtain a private pilot license has to demonstrate theoretical skills on a level equivalent to the privileges granted to the holder of a PPL(A).</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-punkt-8-ledd-2">The requirements and procedures for the theory exam regarding PPL(A) are scheduled in EASA PART-FCL.025.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-6-punkt-9"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">6.9.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-punkt-9-ledd-1">A student working to obtain a commercial pilot license with instrument rating has to demonstrate a knowledge level equivalent to the privileges granted to the holder of a ATPL(A) in accordance with the requirements of EASA PART-FCL.025.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-6-punkt-10"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">6.10.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-punkt-10-ledd-1">A student working to obtain a multi crew pilot license (MPL) has to demonstrate a knowledge level equivalent to the privileges granted to the holder of ATPL(A) in accordance with the requirements in EASA PART-FCL.025.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-punkt-10-ledd-2">The theory exam is arranged by the CAA-N.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-6-punkt-11"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">6.11.</span><span class="miscHeadline"><i>Skilltest</i></span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-punkt-11-ledd-1">When the relevant flight training is completed, the student has to pass the skilltest of PPL(A) using a single-engine aeroplane, the skill test of CPL(A)IR using either a single-engine or a multi-engine aeroplane, and the skill test of MPL(A) using the type of aeroplane which has been used during the most advanced phase of the training.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-punkt-11-ledd-2">The skill test is conducted by the CAA-N.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-6-punkt-12"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">6.12.</span><span class="miscHeadline"><i>Diploma</i></span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-punkt-12-ledd-1">When the course has been completed, and the theory exam has been passed, the students will receive a Notice of examination result from the CAA-N. The result will be presented in the percentage given for each individual exam, as well as information about the total result of the exam.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-6-punkt-13"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">6.13.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-punkt-13-ledd-1">After having passed the skill test, the students will receive the flight crew license from the CAA-N. The License will indicate which privileges the student has been granted, as well as the validation of the license and the privileges.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-6-punkt-13-ledd-2">6.14. On completion of the training the students will receive a diploma from the PFA to attest to the training delivered.</article></article></section><section class="section" data-name="kap7" id="kapittel-7" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2017-09-12-1742/KAPITTEL_7"><h2>7. Complaint about formal errors at the exam. Law of vocational school of education (lov om fagskoleutdanning) § 7</h2><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-7-punkt-1"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">7.1.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-7-punkt-1-ledd-1">A student who has taken the exam, test or other kind of work which are evaluated with grades may complain about formal errors. Such a complaint must be submitted within three weeks after the student has been informed of those grades, and should also be aware of the reason for the complaint.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-7-punkt-1-ledd-2">The complaint shall be addressed to the school.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-7-punkt-2"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">7.2.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-7-punkt-2-ledd-1">The nature of any new sanction may be appealed in accordance with the rules set under chapter 8 below.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-7-punkt-2-ledd-2">The board of the school is the appeals body for decisions made by the school pursuant to the provisions described under this chapter.</article></article></section><section class="section" data-name="kap8" id="kapittel-8" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2017-09-12-1742/KAPITTEL_8"><h2>8. Entitled to explanation. Complaint about the sanction. Law of vocational school of education (lov om fagskoleutdanning) § 8</h2><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-8-punkt-1"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">8.1.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-8-punkt-1-ledd-1">The student is entitled to receive a reason for the sanction. Such a requirement has to be promulgated immediately after the sanction has been announced.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-8-punkt-2"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">8.2.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-8-punkt-2-ledd-1">The reasoning shall be given within two weeks after the student has requested it. If the sanction falls into the written guidelines for sanctions these shall be available for the students after the sanction has been completed.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-8-punkt-3"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">8.3.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-8-punkt-3-ledd-1">A student is entitled to make a complaint in writing regarding the grades of the sanction within three weeks of the announcement of the exam result.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-8-punkt-4"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">8.4.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-8-punkt-4-ledd-1">The reasons for the new sanction under the provisions of this chapter cannot be appealed.</article></article></section><section class="section" data-name="kap9" id="kapittel-9" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2017-09-12-1742/KAPITTEL_9"><h2>9. Cancellation of the exam. Law of vocational school of education (lov om fagskoleutdanning) § 9</h2><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-9-punkt-1"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">9.1.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-9-punkt-1-ledd-1">The board of the school can void the result of an exam or test or other kind of work which is evaluated with grades if the student has gained access to the exam due to false diplomas, documents etc., or if the student either intentionally or through gross negligence has cheated, or in conjunction with the exam or test has intentionally tried to cheat.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-9-punkt-2"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">9.2.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-9-punkt-2-ledd-1">The student can appeal to the national appeal body for vocational school education any such a decision made by the school board.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-9-punkt-3"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">9.3.</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-9-punkt-3-ledd-1">The access to the cancellation notice will be permanently available.</article></article></section><section class="section" data-name="kap10" id="kapittel-10" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2017-09-12-1742/KAPITTEL_10"><h2>10. Exclusion and expulsion. Law of vocational school of education (lov om fagskoleutdanning) § 10</h2><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-10-punkt-1"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">10.1</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-10-punkt-1-ledd-1">A student who, in spite of having received a written warning from the school, repeatedly acts in a way that seems to be seriously disturbing the work of fellow students or for the activities of the school, can, after due consideration by the board, be excluded from the school for up to one year.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-10-punkt-2"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">10.2</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-10-punkt-2-ledd-1">The board can decide that a student who has used a false diploma, other false documents or who has shown any fraudulent behavior ref. chapter 9, or who has cheated or tried to cheat ref. chapter 9, shall be suspended from the training and educational activities at the school for up to one year. This will also apply to a student who has deliberately collaborated with such fraudulent activities</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-10-punkt-3"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">10.3</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-10-punkt-3-ledd-1">Such a resolution requires a two thirds majority of the members of the board. A student has the right to comment before the board makes a decision about exclusion and expulsion. The student can appeal to the national appeal body for vocational school education about any such decision made by the board.</article></article></section><section class="section" data-name="kap11" id="kapittel-11" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2017-09-12-1742/KAPITTEL_11"><h2>11. Assessment of suitability. Law of vocational school of education (lov om fagskoleutdanning) § 11</h2><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-11-punkt-1"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">11.1</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-11-punkt-1-ledd-1">The school is required to assess whether the individual student is suitable for the profession. (Ref. Article 3.8 above) The assessment will take place throughout the entire education.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-11-punkt-2"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">11.2</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-11-punkt-2-ledd-1">The board can decide that a student is not suitable for the profession. If such a decision is made, the student can be expelled from the education.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-11-punkt-3"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">11.3</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-11-punkt-3-ledd-1">A decision made according to Article 11.2 above requires a two thirds majority of the members of the board. A student has the right to comment before the board makes such a decision. The student can appeal to the national appeal body for vocational school education about any such decision made by the board.</article></article></section><section class="section" data-name="kap12" id="kapittel-12" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2017-09-12-1742/KAPITTEL_12"><h2>12. Appeals and appeal bodies. Law of vocational school of education (lov om fagskoleutdanningning) § 13</h2><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-12-punkt-1"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">12.1</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-12-punkt-1-ledd-1">In compliance with the provision stated above, the school has established a local complaints committee for the treatment of individual decisions made by the school. (An individual decision is one which, according to the Law of Administration, forvaltningsloven, § 2b, is a decision which concerns the rights and duties of one or more specific person. No complaint can be registered about administrative decisions made by the school.)</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-12-punkt-1-ledd-2">In addition, the board can decide that the complaints committee may handle other complaints from the students as well as those specified under the provisions of the above Articles 7, 9, 10 and 11. Cases that will be addressed under these provisions cannot be handled by other bodies at the school.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-12-punkt-2"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">12.2</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-12-punkt-2-ledd-1">The local complaints committee consists of five members, each with a personal deputy. The chairman of the committee and his deputy must not be employed at the school. Two of the members of the committee must be students.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-12-punkt-3"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">12.3</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-12-punkt-3-ledd-1">There is no appeal against the decisions made by the local complaints committee regarding individual decisions made by the school.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-12-punkt-4"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">12.4</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-12-punkt-4-ledd-1">The Ministry of Education provides regulations regarding a national appeal body which shall handle complaints within certain areas. (Ref. Articles 10.3 and 11.3 above.)</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-12-punkt-5"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">12.5</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-12-punkt-5-ledd-1">Appeals regarding decisions made by the CAA-N have to be addressed to the CAA-N which is the competent authority for such appeals.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-12-punkt-5-ledd-2">Such appeals follow the guidelines and deadlines adopted by the CAA-N for the handling of complaints.</article></article><article class="marginIdArticle" id="kapittel-12-punkt-6"><span class="data-marginOriginalId">12.6</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-12-punkt-6-ledd-1">As stated under Article 12.5 above, complaints regarding exams arranged by the CAA-N will follow the guidelines and deadlines adopted by the CAA-N for the handling of such complaints.</article></article></section><section class="section" id="kapittel-13" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2017-09-12-1742/KAPITTEL_13"><h2>The entry into force of these provisions</h2><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-13-ledd-1">These provisions are adopted by the board of the PFA at the meeting of 12th of September 2017.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-13-ledd-2">Previous rules are repealed.</article></section></main></body></html>