<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE html>
<html lang="no">
  <head>
    <title>Forskrift om beskyttelse av Parmigiano Reggiano som opprinnelsesbetegnelse</title>
    <base href="https://lovdata.no/"/>
  </head>
  <body>
    <header class="documentHeader" id="hode">
      <dl class="data-document-key-info">
        <dt class="legacyID">Datokode</dt>
        <dd class="legacyID">FOR-2012-04-20-340</dd>
        <dt class="dokid">DokumentID</dt>
        <dd class="dokid">LTI/forskrift/2012-04-20-340</dd>
        <dt class="ministry">Departement</dt>
        <dd class="ministry">
          <ul>
            <li>Landbruks- og matdepartementet</li>
          </ul>
        </dd>
        <dt class="publishedIn">Publisert i</dt>
        <dd class="publishedIn">I 2012 hefte 5 s 799</dd>
        <dt class="dateInForce">I kraft fra</dt>
        <dd class="dateInForce">2012-04-20</dd>
        <dt class="appliesTo">Gjelder for</dt>
        <dd class="appliesTo">Norge</dd>
        <dt class="basedOn">Hjemmel</dt>
        <dd class="basedOn">
          <ul>
            <li>forskrift/2002-07-05-698/&#xA7;15</li>
            <li>lov/2003-12-19-124/&#xA7;30</li>
            <li>forskrift/2003-12-19-1790</li>
          </ul>
        </dd>
        <dt class="dateOfPublication">Kunngjort</dt>
        <dd class="dateOfPublication">2012-04-24 14:50</dd>
        <dt class="journalNumber">Journalnummer</dt>
        <dd class="journalNumber">2012-0294</dd>
        <dt class="titleShort">Korttittel</dt>
        <dd class="titleShort">Forskrift om betegnelsen Parmigiano Reggiano</dd>
        <dt class="title">Tittel</dt>
        <dd class="title">Forskrift om beskyttelse av Parmigiano Reggiano som opprinnelsesbetegnelse</dd>
        <dt class="miscInformation">Annet om dokumentet</dt>
        <dd class="miscInformation"><strong>Hjemmel:</strong> Fastsatt av Mattilsynet 20. april 2012 med hjemmel i forskrift 5. juli 2002 nr. 698 om beskyttelse av opprinnelsesbetegnelser, geografiske betegnelser og betegnelser for tradisjonelt s&#xE6;rpreg p&#xE5; n&#xE6;ringsmidler &#xA7; 15, jf. lov 19. desember 2003 nr. 124 om matproduksjon og mattrygghet mv. (matloven) &#xA7; 30 og delegeringsvedtak 19. desember 2003 nr. 1790.</dd>
        <dt class="refid">RefID</dt>
        <dd class="refid">forskrift/2012-04-20-340</dd>
        <dt class="table-of-contents">Innhold</dt>
        <dd class="table-of-contents">
          <ul class="tocTopUl">
            <li>Forskrift om beskyttelse av Parmigiano Reggiano som opprinnelsesbetegnelse<ul class="tocSubUl"><li>&#xA7; 1. Beskyttet produktbetegnelse</li><li>&#xA7; 2. Rettmessig bruker</li><li>&#xA7; 3. Vilk&#xE5;r for bruk av produktbetegnelsen</li><li>&#xA7; 4. Ikrafttredelse</li><li>N&#xE6;rmere forklaring av innholdet og reguleringsteknikken i produktforskriften</li></ul></li>
          </ul>
        </dd>
      </dl>
    </header>
    <main class="documentBody" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2012-04-20-340" id="dokument">
      <h1>Forskrift om beskyttelse av Parmigiano Reggiano som opprinnelsesbetegnelse</h1>
      <article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2012-04-20-340/&#xA7;1" data-name="&#xA7;1" id="paragraf-1">
        <h2 class="legalArticleHeader"><span class="legalArticleValue">&#xA7; 1</span>. <span class="legalArticleTitle">Beskyttet produktbetegnelse</span></h2>
        <article class="legalP" id="paragraf-1-ledd-1">Parmigiano Reggiano.</article>
      </article>
      <article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2012-04-20-340/&#xA7;2" data-name="&#xA7;2" id="paragraf-2">
        <h2 class="legalArticleHeader"><span class="legalArticleValue">&#xA7; 2</span>. <span class="legalArticleTitle">Rettmessig bruker</span></h2>
        <article class="legalP" id="paragraf-2-ledd-1">Consorzio del Formaggio Parmigiano-Reggiano.</article>
      </article>
      <article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2012-04-20-340/&#xA7;3" data-name="&#xA7;3" id="paragraf-3">
        <h2 class="legalArticleHeader"><span class="legalArticleValue">&#xA7; 3</span>. <span class="legalArticleTitle">Vilk&#xE5;r for bruk av produktbetegnelsen</span></h2>
        <article class="legalP" id="paragraf-3-ledd-1">Parmigiano Reggiano skal produseres, bearbeides, foredles, merkes, pakkes og omsettes i samsvar med bestemmelsene i forordning (EF) nr. 1107/96 om beskyttelse av betegnelsen, jf. produktspesifikasjonen som endret ved forordning (EF) nr. 1571/2003 og forordning (EU) nr. 794/2011 og Single document slik det fremg&#xE5;r av Official Journal OJ C 87, 16.4.2009, s. 14 som korrigert i OJ C 215, 21.7.2011, s. 34.</article>
      </article>
      <article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2012-04-20-340/&#xA7;4" data-name="&#xA7;4" id="paragraf-4">
        <h2 class="legalArticleHeader"><span class="legalArticleValue">&#xA7; 4</span>. <span class="legalArticleTitle">Ikrafttredelse</span></h2>
        <article class="legalP" id="paragraf-4-ledd-1">Forskriften trer i kraft straks.</article>
      </article>
      <section class="section" data-name="kapN" id="kapittel-1" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2012-04-20-340/KAPITTEL_1">
        <h2>N&#xE6;rmere forklaring av innholdet og reguleringsteknikken i produktforskriften</h2>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-1">Teksten nedenfor er kun ment til informasjon og er ikke en del av forskriften.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-2">Parmigiano Reggiano er en italiensk betegnelse som ogs&#xE5; er beskyttet i EU etter forordning (EF) nr. 510/2006 om beskyttelse av geografiske betegnelser og opprinnelsesbetegnelser p&#xE5; landbruksprodukter og n&#xE6;ringsmidler. Forordning (EF) nr. 510/2006 er imidlertid ikke en del av E&#xD8;S-avtaleverket og Norge har per i dag heller ingen andre avtaler med EU om gjensidig godkjenning av avtalepartenes beskyttede betegnelser p&#xE5; n&#xE6;ringsmidler. En betegnelse som er beskyttet etter forordning (EF) nr. 510/2006 er derfor ikke automatisk beskyttet i Norge etter forskrift om beskyttede betegnelser og vice versa. Dersom en betegnelse som er beskyttet i EU ogs&#xE5; skal oppn&#xE5; tilsvarende beskyttelse i Norge, m&#xE5; betegnelsen s&#xF8;kes godkjent og beskyttes etter forskrift om beskyttede betegnelser og vice versa.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-3">Det fremg&#xE5;r av bestemmelsene i forordning (EF) nr. 510/2006 at noen av de mest sentrale rettslige dokumentene som ligger til grunn for beskyttelse av en betegnelse i EU, blant annet er selve vedtaket om beskyttelse av betegnelsen, produktspesifikasjonen og det s&#xE5;kalte Single document. Produktspesifikasjonen inneholder de fullstendige kravene som produkter som skal merkes med den beskyttede betegnelsen m&#xE5; oppfylle og redegj&#xF8;r fullstendig for blant annet sammenhengen mellom produktets egenskaper og den geografiske opprinnelsen. Single document inneholder et sammendrag av de mest sentrale elementene i produktspesifikasjonen.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-4">Mange EU-land hadde nasjonale ordninger for beskyttelse av betegnelser p&#xE5; n&#xE6;ringsmidler i tiden f&#xF8;r EU for f&#xF8;rste gang lagde sitt felles regelverk om beskyttelse av betegnelser p&#xE5; n&#xE6;ringsmidler p&#xE5; unionsniv&#xE5; i forordning (EF) nr. 2081/92 (som n&#xE5; er opphevet og erstattet av forordning (EF) nr. 510/2006). Forordning (EF) nr. 2081/92 inneholdt blant annet en bestemmelse om at medlemsstatene innen en viss frist kunne melde inn de betegnelsene som da var beskyttet nasjonalt for vurdering med tanke p&#xE5; beskyttelse p&#xE5; EU-niv&#xE5;. Etter denne prosedyren ble blant annet betegnelsen Parmigiano Reggiano meldt inn av Italia. Etter at alle de innmeldte betegnelsene var vurdert etter kravene i forordning (EF) nr. 2081/92, fattet Kommisjonen i forordning (EF) nr. 1107/96 et samlevedtak om beskyttelse av de betegnelsene som oppfyller kravene. Det er forordning (EF) nr. 1107/96 som beskytter blant annet Parmigiano Reggiano som opprinnelsesbetegnelse i EU, men forordningen inneholder for &#xF8;vrig ingen bestemmelser om de n&#xE6;rmere kravene til den enkelte betegnelsen.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-5">I produktforskriften &#xA7; 3, om vilk&#xE5;r for bruk av produktbetegnelsen, har vi derfor tatt inn henvisninger til kravene i vedtaket om beskyttelse av Parmigiano Reggiano i EU i forordning (EF) nr. 1107/96, produktspesifikasjonen som endret ved forordning (EF) nr. 1571/2003 og forordning (EU) nr. 794/2011 og det oppdaterte Single document slik det fremg&#xE5;r av Official Journal OJ C 87, 16.4.2009, s. 14 som korrigert i OJ C 215, 21.7.2011, s. 34. Reguleringsteknikken likner derfor mye p&#xE5; metoden som brukes for gjennomf&#xF8;ring i norsk rett av E&#xD8;S-forpliktelser i form av forordninger.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-6">Nedenfor f&#xF8;lger til informasjon og som et hjelpemiddel ved lesing av &#xA7; 3 i produktforskriften, en konsolidert engelsk versjon av det oppdaterte Single document for Parmigiano Reggiano slik det det fremg&#xE5;r av Official Journal OJ C 87, 16.4.2009, s. 14 som korrigert i OJ C 215, 21.7.2011, s. 34. Ingen av de rettslige dokumentene som ligger til grunn for beskyttelse av betegnelsen i EU vil bli oversatt til norsk. Teksten nedenfor er som nevnt innledningsvis kun ment til informasjon og er ikke en del av forskriften.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">SINGLE DOCUMENT</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">COUNCIL REGULATION (EC) No 510/2006<p class="leddfortsettelse">&#xAB;PARMIGIANO REGGIANO&#xBB;</p><p class="leddfortsettelse">EC No: IT-PDO-0317-0016- 26.7.2007</p><p class="leddfortsettelse">PGI ( ) PDO ( X )</p></article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">1. Name:</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-7">&#xAB;Parmigiano Reggiano&#xBB;.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">2. Member State or Third Country:</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-8">Italy.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">3. Description of the agricultural product or foodstuff:</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">3.1. Type of product (Annex II)</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-9">Class 1.3. Cheeses.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">3.2. Description of the product to which the name in (1) applies</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-10">&#xAB;Parmigiano Reggiano&#xBB; is a hard cheese, cooked and slowly matured cheese, made from raw cow's milk, partially skimmed by natural surface skimming. The milk must not undergo any heat treatment and must come from cows fed primarily on fodder obtained in the area of origin. It must be matured for at least 12 months. &#xAB;Parmigiano Reggiano&#xBB; can be sold on the market as a whole cheese, portions or grated.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-11">&#xAB;Parmigiano Reggiano&#xBB; shall have the following characteristics:<ul class="defaultList"><li data-li-identifier="-" data-name="-"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-1-ledd-11-punkt-1"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-11-punkt-1-ledd-1">cylindrical in form with a slightly convex or virtually straight heel, with flat faces with a slightly raised edge,</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="-" data-name="-"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-1-ledd-11-punkt-2"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-11-punkt-2-ledd-1">dimensions: diameter of the flat faces 35 to 45 cm, heel height 20 to 26 cm,</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="-" data-name="-"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-1-ledd-11-punkt-3"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-11-punkt-3-ledd-1">minimum weight of each wheel of cheese: 30 kg,</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="-" data-name="-"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-1-ledd-11-punkt-4"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-11-punkt-4-ledd-1">external appearance: crust of a natural straw colour,</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="-" data-name="-"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-1-ledd-11-punkt-5"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-11-punkt-5-ledd-1">thickness of the crust: approximately 6 mm,</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="-" data-name="-"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-1-ledd-11-punkt-6"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-11-punkt-6-ledd-1">colour of the body of the cheese: between light straw-coloured and straw-coloured,</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="-" data-name="-"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-1-ledd-11-punkt-7"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-11-punkt-7-ledd-1">characteristic aroma and taste: fragrant, delicate, flavoursome but not pungent,</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="-" data-name="-"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-1-ledd-11-punkt-8"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-11-punkt-8-ledd-1">texture of the body of the cheese: fine grained, flaky,</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="-" data-name="-"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-1-ledd-11-punkt-9"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-11-punkt-9-ledd-1">fat content per dry matter: 32&#xA0;% minimum.</article></article></li></ul></article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">3.3. Raw materials (for processed products only)</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-12">Cow's milk, salt, calf rennet.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-13">The milk comes from cows reared in the defined geographical area.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-14">The use of additives is not permitted.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">3.4. Feed (for products of animal origin only)</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-15">The cows are fed primarily on fodder from the defined geographical area, specified by quantity and quality.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-16">At least 75&#xA0;% of the dry matter of the fodder must be produced within the geographical area.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-17">Feeding stuffs may make up at most 50&#xA0;% by weight of the dry matter of the animal food.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-18">The use of silage of any kind is prohibited.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">3.5. Specific steps in production that must take place in the identified geographical area</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-19">The farms rearing the dairy cows whose milk is to be processed into &#xAB;Parmigiano Reggiano&#xBB; are located within the defined geographical area.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-20">The milk must be produced and processed within the defined geographical area. The milk obtained from the evening milking and the morning milking is delivered in whole raw state to the dairy, in line with production specifications. The milk from the morning milking is placed in copper vats and mixed with that from the evening milking, partially skimmed by natural surface skimming. Native whey is added to the milk. The use of selected starters is not permitted. Following coagulation, obtained exclusively by the use of calf rennet, the curd is broken up and cooked. After sedimentation, the cheese mass is transferred to the appropriate moulds to form the wheels. Markings are then affixed. After several days, the wheels are immersed in brine and then matured for a period of at least 12 months.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-21">The minimum 12-month maturing must be carried out in the defined geographical area.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-22">After the minimum maturing period, examination by experts is carried out to check compliance with production specifications.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">3.6. Specific rules concerning slicing, grating, packaging, etc.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-23">&#xAB;Parmigiano Reggiano&#xBB; can be sold on the market as a whole cheese, portions or grated.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-24">For the sake of consumer protection, in order to guarantee the authenticity of pre-packaged, grated or portioned &#xAB;Parmigiano Reggiano&#xBB; placed on the market, the grating, portioning and subsequent packaging operations must be carried out in the defined geographical area. This is required because the marks identifying &#xAB;Parmigiano Reggiano&#xBB; on the whole cheese are lost or not visible on the grated or portioned product, making it necessary to guarantee the origin of the pre-packaged product. It is also required because of the need to guarantee that the cheese is packaged quickly after portioning using appropriate methods to prevent the cheese being dehydrated, oxidised or losing its original &#xAB;Parmigiano Reggiano&#xBB; organoleptic characteristics. Cutting into the cheese wheel deprives the cheese of the natural protection provided by the crust which, being itself highly dehydrated, insulates the cheese very well against the ambient air.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-25">Portions of Parmigiano Reggiano may be packaged in the retail outlet in which they are prepared.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-26">Only the whole cheese bearing the protected designation of origin (PDO) &#xAB;Parmigiano Reggiano&#xBB; may be grated; it must be packaged immediately afterwards, without any processing or addition of substances likely to modify its conservation properties or original organoleptic characteristics.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">3.7. Specific rules concerning labelling</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-27">The identification marks on each wheel of &#xAB;Parmigiano Reggiano&#xBB; cheese comprise the words &#xAB;Parmigiano Reggiano&#xBB; next to the registration number of the dairy and the year and month of production stencilled onto the surface of the heel, the oval stamp with the words &#xAB;Parmigiano Reggiano Consorzio Tutela&#xBB;, and a casein nameplate showing the codes identifying the mould and, where appropriate, the mark identifying a second class cheese.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-28">The identification mark for pre-packaged, grated and portioned &#xAB;Parmigiano Reggiano&#xBB; cheese placed on the market comprises, in the top part, the image of a segment and a wheel of &#xAB;Parmigiano Reggiano&#xBB; cheese next to a knife and, at the bottom, the words &#xAB;PARMIGIANO REGGIANO&#xBB;. This mark, which is a mandatory component of the label, must be reproduced in accordance with the technical specifications defined by the consortium in the relevant agreement.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">4. Concise definition of the geographical area</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-29">The defined geographical area comprises the territories of the Provinces of Bologna to the left of the Reno River, Mantua to the right of the River Po, Modena, Parma and Reggio in the Emilia Region.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">5. Link with the geographical area</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">5.1. Specificity of the geographical area</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-30">In terms of the natural factors involved, particular attention should be drawn to the soil characteristics of the land within the defined geographical area, extending from the Appenine ridge to the Po, in combination with climate conditions which have a direct influence on both the composition of the natural flora and the specific fermentation characteristics of the product. In human terms, in addition to the historic relevance of the cheese in the local economy, it should be noted that the complex operations to which &#xAB;Parmigiano Reggiano&#xBB; cheese is subjected are the fruit of traditional cheese-making techniques established over the centuries in this production area and faithfully handed down as consistent local practices.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">5.2. Specificity of the product</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-31">The specific characteristics of &#xAB;Parmigiano Reggiano&#xBB; cheese are the structure of the body of the cheese, fine grained and flaky, the fragrant aroma and delicate taste, which is flavoursome without being pungent, and its high level of solubility and digestibility.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-32">These characteristics stem from the specific features of and selection criteria applied to the milk used raw on a daily basis in copper vats, coagulated with calf rennet with a high chymosin content, from the curing in saturated brine and prolonged maturation period.</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">5.3. Causal link between the geographical area and the quality or characteristics of the product (for PDO) or a specific quality, the reputation or other characteristic of the product (for PGI)</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-33">The peculiar physical, chemical and microbiological properties of the milk which ensure the specific characteristics and quality of &#xAB;Parmigiano Reggiano&#xBB; cheese are basically due to the manner in which the dairy cows are fed, on a basis of fodder from the original area, strictly excluding the use of silage of any kind.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-34">The minimum twelve-month maturing period, carried out within the geographical area defined by virtue of its specific climatic conditions is a necessary phase in order to ensure that the product obtained from the processing of the milk can acquire, through particular enzyme processes, the characteristics proper to a &#xAB;Parmigiano Reggiano&#xBB; cheese.</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-35">Reference to publication of the specification:</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-36">(Article 5(7) of Regulation (EC) No 510/2006)</article>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-37">The full text of the product specification is available:<ul class="defaultList"><li data-li-identifier="-" data-name="-"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-1-ledd-37-punkt-1"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-37-punkt-1-ledd-1">at the following website: www.politicheagricole.it/DocumentiPubblicazioni/Search_Documenti_Elenco.htm?txtTipoDocumento=Disciplinare%20in%20esame%20UE&amp;txtDocArgomento=Prodotti%20di%20Qualit%E0&gt;Prodotti%20Dop,%20Igp%20e%20Stg<br/>or: <ul class="defaultList"><li data-li-identifier="-" data-name="-"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-1-ledd-37-punkt-1-ledd-1-punkt-1"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-37-punkt-1-ledd-1-punkt-1-ledd-1">by going directly to the home page of the Ministry (www.politicheagricole.it) and clicking on &#xAB;Prodotti di Qualit&#xE0;&#xBB; (on the left of the screen) and finally on &#xAB;Disciplinari di Produzione all'esame dell'UE (Reg CE 510/2006)&#xBB;.</article></article></li></ul></article></article></li></ul></article>
      </section>
    </main>
  </body>
</html>
