<!DOCTYPE html><html lang="no"><head><title>Forskrift om endring i forskrift om særskilte beskyttelsestiltak ved import av visse næringsmidler fra tredjestater på grunn av pesticidrisiko mfl.</title><base href="https://lovdata.no/" /></head><body><header class="documentHeader" id="hode"><dl class="data-document-key-info"><dt class="legacyID">Datokode</dt><dd class="legacyID">FOR-2018-11-19-1773</dd><dt class="dokid">DokumentID</dt><dd class="dokid">LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773</dd><dt class="ministry">Departement</dt><dd class="ministry"><ul><li>Nærings- og fiskeridepartementet</li><li>Landbruks- og matdepartementet</li><li>Helse- og omsorgsdepartementet</li></ul></dd><dt class="dateInForce">I kraft fra</dt><dd class="dateInForce">2018-12-08</dd><dt class="changesToDocuments">Endrer</dt><dd class="changesToDocuments"><ul><li>forskrift/2014-09-02-1141</li><li>forskrift/2008-12-22-1621</li></ul></dd><dt class="appliesTo">Gjelder for</dt><dd class="appliesTo">Norge</dd><dt class="basedOn">Hjemmel</dt><dd class="basedOn"><ul><li>lov/2003-12-19-124/§23</li><li>lov/2003-12-19-124/§16</li><li>lov/2003-12-19-124/§17</li><li>forskrift/2003-12-19-1790</li><li>forskrift/2004-05-05-884</li></ul></dd><dt class="dateOfPublication">Kunngjort</dt><dd class="dateOfPublication">2018-11-29 14:05</dd><dt class="journalNumber">Journalnummer</dt><dd class="journalNumber">2018-1032</dd><dt class="titleShort">Korttittel</dt><dd class="titleShort">Endr. i forskrift om import av visse næringsmidler fra tredjestater mfl.</dd><dt class="title">Tittel</dt><dd class="title">Forskrift om endring i forskrift om særskilte beskyttelsestiltak ved import av visse næringsmidler fra tredjestater på grunn av pesticidrisiko mfl.</dd><dt class="miscInformation">Annet om dokumentet</dt><dd class="miscInformation"><strong>Hjemmel:</strong> Fastsatt av Mattilsynet 19. november 2018 med hjemmel i lov 19. desember 2003 nr. 124 om matproduksjon og mattrygghet mv. (matloven) § 23 tredje ledd, jf. § 16 og § 17, jf. delegeringsvedtak 19. desember 2003 nr. 1790 og delegeringsvedtak 5. mai 2004 nr. 884. <br /><strong>EØS-henvisninger:</strong> EØS-avtalen vedlegg I kap. I del 7.1 nr. 13, kap. II nr. 41 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) 2018/1660).</dd><dt class="refid">RefID</dt><dd class="refid">forskrift/2018-11-19-1773</dd><dt class="table-of-contents">Innhold</dt><dd class="table-of-contents"><ul class="tocTopUl"><li>Forskrift om endring i forskrift om særskilte beskyttelsestiltak ved import av visse næringsmidler fra tredjestater på grunn av pesticidrisiko mfl.<ul class="tocSubUl"><li>I</li><li>II</li><li>III</li><li>Forordninger<ul class="tocSubUl"><li>COMMISSION IMPLEMENTING REGULATION (EU) 2018/1660 of 7 November 2018 imposing special conditions governing the import of certain food of non-animal origin from certain third countries due to the risks of contamination with pesticides residues, amending Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 and repealing Implementing Regulation (EU) No 885/2014<ul class="tocSubUl"><li>Article 1 Scope</li><li>Article 2 Definitions</li><li>Article 3 Import into the Union</li><li>Article 4 Results of sampling and analysis</li><li>Article 5 Health certificate</li><li>Article 6 Identification</li><li>Article 7 Prior notification of consignments</li><li>Article 8 Official controls</li><li>Article 9 Splitting of a consignment</li><li>Article 10 Release for free circulation</li><li>Article 11 Non-compliance</li><li>Article 12 Reports</li><li>Article 13 Review</li><li>Article 14 Costs</li><li>Article 15 Amendment to Regulation (EC) No 669/2009</li><li>Article 16 Repeal</li><li>Article 17 Transitional measures</li><li>Article 18 Entry into force and date of application</li><li>Vedlegg I til forordning (EU) 2018/1660 Food of non-animal origin subject to special conditions regarding their import into the European Union:</li><li>Vedlegg II til forordning (EU) 2018/1660</li></ul></li></ul></li><li>Forordninger i pdf</li></ul></li></ul></dd></dl></header><main class="documentBody" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773" id="dokument"><h1>Forskrift om endring i forskrift om særskilte beskyttelsestiltak ved import av visse næringsmidler fra tredjestater på grunn av pesticidrisiko mfl.</h1><section class="section" data-name="kapI" id="kapittel-1" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/KAPITTEL_1"><h2 data-text-align="center">I</h2><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-1">I forskrift 2. september 2014 nr. 1141 om særskilte beskyttelsestiltak ved import av visse næringsmidler fra tredjestater på grunn av pesticidrisiko gjøres følgende endringer:</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Tittel på forskriften skal lyde:</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true"><i>Forskrift om særskilte beskyttelsestiltak ved import av visse næringsmidler fra tredjestater på grunn av risiko for plantevernmidler</i></article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">EØS-henvisningsfeltet skal lyde:</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-2">EØS-avtalen vedlegg I kap. I del 7.1 nr. 13, kap. II nr. 41 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) 2018/1660).</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">§ 1 første ledd skal lyde:</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-3">Forskriften gjelder utvidet kontroll ved import av karriblader fra India, vinblader fra Tyrkia og Pitahaya (dragefrukt) fra Vietnam til bruk som næringsmidler når Norge er innførselssted i EØS-området.</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">§ 2 skal lyde:</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-4">EØS-avtalens vedlegg I kap. I del 7.1 nr. 13, kap. II nr. 41 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) 2018/1660) om særlige importbetingelser for visse næringsmidler av ikke-animalsk opprinnelse fra visse tredjestater som følge av risikoen for forurensning med rester av plantevernmidler, om endring av forordning (EF) nr. 669/2009 og om opphevelse av gjennomføringsforordning (EU) nr. 885/2014, gjelder som forskrift med de tilpasninger som følger av vedlegg I og II, protokoll 1 til avtalen og avtalen for øvrig.</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">§ 3 første ledd skal lyde:</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-5">Mattilsynets grensekontrollstasjoner ved Oslo lufthavn, Oslo havn, Borg havn og Larvik havn utpekes som innførselssteder (DPE) i henhold til forordning (EU) 2018/1660 artikkel 7.</article></section><section class="section" data-name="kapII" id="kapittel-2" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/KAPITTEL_2"><h2 data-text-align="center">II</h2><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-2-ledd-1">I forskrift 22. desember 2008 nr. 1621 om offentlig kontroll med etterlevelse av regelverk om fôrvarer, næringsmidler og helse og velferd hos dyr (kontrollforskriften) gjøres følgende endringer:</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">EØS-henvisningsfeltet skal lyde:</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-2-ledd-2">EØS-avtalen vedlegg I kap. I del 1.1 nr. 11, kap. II nr. 31j, nr. 31o (forordning (EF) nr. 152/2009 som endret ved forordning (EU) nr. 278/2012, forordning (EU) nr. 51/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 691/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 709/2014 og forordning (EU) 2017/771), nr. 47, vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzi (forordning (EF) nr. 882/2004 som endret ved forordning (EF) nr. 776/2006, forordning (EF) nr. 180/2008 (som endret ved forordning (EU) nr. 208/2011, forordning (EU) nr. 72/2013 og forordning (EU) 2017/793), forordning (EF) nr. 301/2008, forordning (EF) nr. 737/2008, forordning (EF) nr. 1029/2008, forordning (EU) nr. 208/2011, forordning (EU) nr. 880/2011, forordning (EU) nr. 563/2012, forordning (EU) nr. 517/2013, forordning (EU) 2017/140, forordning (EU) 2017/212, forordning (EU) 2017/2460 og forordning (EU) 2018/222), nr. 54zzzzo (forordning (EF) nr. 669/2009 som endret ved forordning (EU) nr. 212/2010, forordning (EU) nr. 878/2010, forordning (EU) nr. 1099/2010, forordning (EU) nr. 187/2011, forordning (EU) nr. 433/2011, forordning (EU) nr. 799/2011, forordning (EU) nr. 1277/2011 og forordning (EU) nr. 294/2012), vedlegg I kap. I del 1.2 nr. 153 (forordning (EU) 2016/1843) vedlegg I kap. I del 3.2 nr. 41 og nr. 47 (forordning (EU) nr. 415/2013), vedlegg I kap. I del 7.1 nr. 13, kap. II nr. 41 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) nr. 514/2012, forordning (EU) nr. 889/2012, forordning (EU) nr. 1235/2012, forordning (EU) nr. 91/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 270/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 618/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 925/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 1355/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 323/2014, forordning (EU) nr. 718/2014, forordning (EU) nr. 1021/2014, forordning (EU) nr. 1295/2014, forordning (EU) 2015/525, forordning (EU) 2015/943, forordning (EU) 2015/1012, forordning (EU) 2015/1607, forordning (EU) 2015/2383, forordning (EU) 2016/24, forordning (EU) 2016/166, forordning (EU) 2016/443, forordning (EU) 2016/1024, forordning (EU) 2016/2107, forordning (EU) 2017/186, forordning (EU) 2017/1142, forordning (EU) 2017/2298, forordning (EU) 2018/941 og forordning (EU) 2018/1660).</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">§ 3 skal lyde:</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-2-ledd-3">EØS-avtalen vedlegg I kapittel II nr. 47 og vedlegg II kapittel XII nr. 54zzzzo (forordning (EF) nr. 669/2009 som endret ved forordning (EU) nr. 212/2010, forordning (EU) nr. 878/2010, forordning (EU) nr. 1099/2010, forordning (EU) nr. 187/2011, forordning (EU) nr. 433/2011, forordning (EU) nr. 799/2011, forordning (EU) nr. 1277/2011 og forordning (EU) nr. 294/2012), vedlegg I kapittel I del 7.1 nr. 13, kap. II nr. 41 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) nr. 514/2012, forordning (EU) nr. 889/2012, forordning (EU) nr. 1235/2012, forordning (EU) nr. 91/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 270/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 618/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 925/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 1355/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 323/2014, forordning (EU) nr. 718/2014, forordning (EU) nr. 1021/2014, forordning (EU) nr. 1295/2014, forordning (EU) 2015/525, forordning (EU) 2015/943, forordning (EU) 2015/1012, forordning (EU) 2015/1607, forordning (EU) 2015/2383, forordning (EU) 2016/24, forordning (EU) 2016/166, forordning (EU) 2016/443, forordning (EU) 2016/1024, forordning (EU) 2016/2107, forordning (EU) 2017/186, forordning (EU) 2017/1142, forordning (EU) 2017/2298, forordning (EU) 2018/941 og forordning (EU) 2018/1660) om gjennomføring av europaparlaments og rådsforordning (EF) nr. 882/2004 med hensyn til strengere offentlig kontroll ved import av visse fôrvarer og næringsmidler av ikke-animalsk opprinnelse, og om endring av vedtak 2006/504/EF gjelder som forskrift med de tilpasninger som følger av vedlegg I og II, protokoll 1 til avtalen og avtalen for øvrig.</article></section><section class="section" data-name="kapIII" id="kapittel-3" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/KAPITTEL_3"><h2 data-text-align="center">III</h2><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-ledd-1">Endringene trer i kraft 8. desember 2018.</article></section><section class="section" id="kapittel-4" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/KAPITTEL_4"><h2>Forordninger</h2><article class="centeredP" data-text-align="center">I</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-ledd-1">I forskrift 2. september 2014 nr. 1141 om særskilte beskyttelsestiltak ved import av visse næringsmidler fra tredjestater på grunn av pesticidrisiko gjøres følgende endringer i avsnittet om forordninger:</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Hele avsnittet om Konsolidert forordning (EU) nr. 885/2014 (engelsk) slettes og erstattes av:</article><span class="futuretitle" id="kapittel-4-foreslåttittel-1">Forordning (EU) 2018/1660 (engelsk)</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-ledd-2">Nedenfor gjengis til informasjon EØS-avtalen vedlegg I kapittel I del 7.1 nr. 13, kap. II nr. 41 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) 2018/1660) med de endringer og tillegg som følger av EØS-tilpasningen av rettsakten i samsvar med vedlegg I og II til EØS-avtalen.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-ledd-3">Sertifikatet nevnt i artikkel 5 finnes under vedlegg II i pdf-filen nedenfor.</article><section class="section" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/KAPITTEL_4-1"><h3 data-text-align="center">COMMISSION IMPLEMENTING REGULATION (EU) 2018/1660<br />of 7 November 2018<br />imposing special conditions governing the import of certain food of non-animal origin from certain third countries due to the risks of contamination with pesticides residues, amending Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 and repealing Implementing Regulation (EU) No 885/2014</h3><article class="defaultP">(Text with EEA relevance)</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">THE EUROPEAN COMMISSION,</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-ledd-1">Having regard to the Treaty on the Functioning of the European Union,</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-ledd-2">Having regard to Regulation (EC) No 178/2002 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 28 January 2002 laying down the general principles and requirements of food law, establishing the European Food Safety Authority and laying down procedures in matters of food safety,<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="1" data-unique-footnote-counter="1">1</sup> and in particular Article 53(1)(b)(ii) thereof,</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-ledd-3">Having regard to Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 29 April 2004 on official controls performed to ensure the verification of compliance with feed and food law, animal health and animal welfare rules,<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="2" data-unique-footnote-counter="2">2</sup> and in particular Article 15(5) thereof,</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-ledd-4">Whereas:</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="1" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-nummer-1">(1) Article 53 of Regulation (EC) No 178/2002 provides for the possibility to adopt appropriate Union emergency measures for food and feed imported from a third country in order to protect public health, animal health or the environment, where it is evident that the food and feed concerned is likely to constitute a serious risk to human health and animal health and that such risk cannot be contained satisfactorily by means of measures taken by the Member States individually. Those Union emergency measures may consist of imposing special conditions of import for the products concerned.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="2" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-nummer-2">(2) Commission Regulation (EC) No 669/2009<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="3">3</sup> provides for an increased level of official controls on imports of the feed and food of non-animal origin listed in Annex I thereof. Vine leaves from Turkey and Pitahaya (dragonfruit) from Vietnam are included in that Annex and are therefore subject to an increased level of official controls.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="3" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-nummer-3">(3) The results from the official controls carried out by the Member States in the framework of Regulation (EC) No 669/2009, data resulting from notifications received through the Rapid Alert System for Food and Feed, as established by Regulation (EC) No 178/2002, audit reports by the Commission, reports received from third countries and exchanges of information between the Commission, Member States and the European Food Safety Authority show a continuous high frequency of non-compliance of vine leaves from Turkey with the maximum residue levels of pesticides set out in Regulation (EC) No 396/2005 of the European Parliament and of the Council.<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="4" data-unique-footnote-counter="4">4</sup> No improvement of the situation could therefore be observed even after increasing the frequency of controls at Union borders.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="4" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-nummer-4">(4) The results from the official controls carried out by the Member States in the framework of Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 show a high frequency of non-compliance of Pitahaya (dragon fruit) from Vietnam with the maximum residue levels of pesticides set out in Regulation (EC) No 396/2005. Moreover, an audit carried out by the Commission in Vietnam in March 2017 to evaluate controls of pesticides in food of plant origin intended for export to the European Union found that there is no official effective pesticide control system for food exported to the Union and that the authorities cannot ensure compliance of Vietnamese products with maximum residue levels for pesticide residues.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="5" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-nummer-5">(5) This provides evidence that the import of vine leaves from Turkey and of Pitahaya (dragon fruit) from Vietnam is likely to constitute a serious risk to health and that such risk cannot be contained satisfactorily by the measures currently in place. It is therefore necessary to establish special conditions of import for vine leaves from Turkey and Pitahaya (dragon fruit) from Vietnam.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="6" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-nummer-6">(6) Curry leaves from India are currently subject to the special conditions of import set out in Commission Implementing Regulation (EU) No 885/2014.<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="5" data-unique-footnote-counter="5">5</sup> Special conditions of import for this product should be maintained, in light of the data resulting from notifications received through the Rapid Alert System for Food and Feed and of the results from the official controls carried out by the Member States in the framework of Implementing Regulation (EU) No 885/2014, which show a continuous high frequency of non-compliance.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="7" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-nummer-7">(7) It is therefore appropriate to require that curry leaves from India, vines leaves from Turkey and Pitahaya (dragon fruit) from Vietnam be subject to official controls before export to the Union, including sampling and analysis, so as to ensure that those products comply with the relevant legal requirements. All consignments of such products should be accompanied by a health certificate stating that the products have been sampled in accordance with Commission Directive 2002/63/EC.<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="6" data-unique-footnote-counter="6">6</sup></article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="8" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-nummer-8">(8) In order to ensure an efficient organisation and a degree of uniformity at the Union level of the controls at import with regard to the presence of pesticides residues in and on curry leaves from India, vines leaves from Turkey and Pitahaya (dragon fruit) from Vietnam, it is appropriate to provide in this Regulation for control procedures which are at least equivalent to those provided for in Regulation (EC) No 669/2009.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="9" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-nummer-9">(9) In order to take into account the specific nature of non-compliance with documentary requirements, it is appropriate to lay down rules on the action to be taken where the consignment is not accompanied by both the results of sampling and analysis and the health certificate or where those results or that health certificate do not comply with the requirements laid down in this Regulation.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="10" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-nummer-10">(10) Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 requires competent authorities to notify the Commission and other Member States of border rejections. As regards pesticides, it is appropriate to clarify that where the competent authorities reject a consignment of food listed in this Regulation, such notification should be made where a maximum residue level set out in Regulation (EC) No 396/2005 has not been complied with, irrespective of whether the acute reference dose has been exceeded.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="11" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-nummer-11">(11) In order to collect data for continuous risk evaluation in relation to the goods covered by this Regulation and adapt existing measures as necessary, it is appropriate to require Member States to submit to the Commission biannually a report on all analytical results of official controls carried out under this Regulation. Certain Member States register the common entry document pertaining to certain feed and food of non-animal origin on a voluntary basis in the Trade Control and Expert System (TRACES) established by Commission Decisions 2003/24/EC<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="7" data-unique-footnote-counter="7">7</sup> and 2004/292/EC,<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="8" data-unique-footnote-counter="8">8</sup> thus providing the Commission with information on the number of consignments imported and the results of the checks provided for in this Regulation. That reporting obligation should therefore be deemed to be satisfied where Member States register in TRACES the common entry documents issued in accordance with this Regulation.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="12" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-nummer-12">(12) The measures provided for in this Regulation should be reviewed before 31 October 2019 in order to assess whether they are still necessary.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="13" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-nummer-13">(13) Adequate financial resources should be available for organising official controls in accordance with this Regulation. Hence, costs resulting from such official controls should be borne by the food business operators responsible for the consignments.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="14" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-nummer-14">(14) For the sake of transparency and consistency of the applicable rules, all specific conditions governing the import of curry leaves from India, of vine leaves from Turkey and of Pitahaya (dragon fruit) from Vietnam with regard to the presence of pesticide residues should be set out in this Regulation. Therefore the entries for vine leaves from Turkey and for Pitahaya (dragon fruit) from Vietnam should be removed from Annex I to Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 and Implementing Regulation (EU) No 885/2014 concerning curry leaves from India should be repealed.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="15" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-nummer-15">(15) In order to give operators sufficient time to adapt to the requirements set out in this Regulation, this Regulation should apply from 8 December 2018. In the interest of legal certainty, it is appropriate to provide that Member States should authorise during a transitional period the import of consignments of vine leaves from Turkey, of Pitahaya (dragon fruit) from Vietnam and of curry leaves from India which left their country of origin or the country of consignment if that country is different from the country of origin, prior to 8 December 2018 provided that those consignments fulfil the requirements of Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 in force on 7 December 2018 and Implementing Regulation (EU) No 885/2014 respectively.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="16" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-nummer-16">(16) The measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on Plants, Animals, Food and Feed,</article><footer class="footnotes"><article class="footnote" data-name="1" data-unique-footnote-counter="1"><span class="footnoteLabel">1</span> OJ L 31, 1.2.2002, p. 1.</article><article class="footnote" data-name="2" data-unique-footnote-counter="2"><span class="footnoteLabel">2</span> OJ L 165, 30.4.2004, p. 1.</article><article class="footnote" data-name="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="3"><span class="footnoteLabel">3</span> Commission Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 of 24 July 2009 implementing Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 of the European Parliament and of the Council as regards the increased level of official controls on imports of certain feed and food of non-animal origin and amending Decision 2006/504/EC (OJ L 194, 25.7.2009, p. 11).</article><article class="footnote" data-name="4" data-unique-footnote-counter="4"><span class="footnoteLabel">4</span> Regulation (EC) No 396/2005 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 23 February 2005 on maximum residue levels of pesticides in or on food and feed of plant and animal origin and amending Council Directive 91/414/EEC (OJ L 70, 16.3.2005, p. 1).</article><article class="footnote" data-name="5" data-unique-footnote-counter="5"><span class="footnoteLabel">5</span> Commission Implementing Regulation (EU) No 885/2014 of 13 August 2014 laying down specific conditions applicable to the import of okra and curry leaves from India and repealing Implementing Regulation (EU) No 91/2013 (OJ L 242, 14.8.2014, p. 20).</article><article class="footnote" data-name="6" data-unique-footnote-counter="6"><span class="footnoteLabel">6</span> Commission Directive 2002/63/EC of 11 July 2002 establishing Community methods of sampling for the official control of pesticide residues in and on products of plant and animal origin and repealing Directive 79/700/EEC (OJ L 187, 16.7.2002, p. 30).</article><article class="footnote" data-name="7" data-unique-footnote-counter="7"><span class="footnoteLabel">7</span> Commission Decision 2003/24/EC of 30 December 2002 concerning the development of an integrated computerised veterinary system.</article><article class="footnote" data-name="8" data-unique-footnote-counter="8"><span class="footnoteLabel">8</span> Commission Decision 2004/292/EC of 30 March 2004 on the introduction of the Traces system and amending Decision 92/486/EEC (OJ L 94, 31.3.2004, p. 63).</article></footer> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</article><article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/a1" data-name="a1" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-1"><h4 class="legalArticleHeader" data-text-align="center"><span class="legalArticleValue">Article 1</span><br /><span class="legalArticleTitle">Scope</span></h4><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="1" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-1-nummer-1">1. This Regulation shall apply to consignments of the food of non-animal origin which is listed in Annex I.<article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-1-nummer-1-ledd-1">This Regulation shall also apply to compound food, containing any of the food listed in Annex I in a quantity above 20&#xa0;%.</article></article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="2" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-1-nummer-2">2. This Regulation shall not apply to consignments of food which are destined to a private person for personal consumption and use only. In case of doubt, the burden of proof lies with the recipient of the consignment.</article></article><article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/a2" data-name="a2" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-2"><h4 class="legalArticleHeader" data-text-align="center"><span class="legalArticleValue">Article 2</span><br /><span class="legalArticleTitle">Definitions</span></h4><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-2-ledd-1">For the purposes of this Regulation, the definitions laid down in Articles 2 and 3 of Regulation (EC) No 178/2002 and in Article 2 of Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 shall apply.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-2-ledd-2">The definitions of ‘common entry document’ and ‘designated point of entry’ set out in points (a) and (b) respectively of Article 3 of Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 shall also apply.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-2-ledd-3">For the purposes of this Regulation, a ‘consignment’ means a ‘lot’ as defined in Directive 2002/63/EC.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-2-ledd-4">For the purposes of Article 11(3), the definitions set out in Regulation (EC) No 396/2005 shall apply.</article></article><article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/a3" data-name="a3" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-3"><h4 class="legalArticleHeader" data-text-align="center"><span class="legalArticleValue">Article 3</span><br /><span class="legalArticleTitle">Import into the Union</span></h4><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-3-ledd-1">Consignments of food referred to in Article 1(1) may only be imported into the Union in accordance with the procedures laid down in this Regulation.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-3-ledd-2">Such consignments can only enter the Union through a designated point of entry.</article></article><article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/a4" data-name="a4" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-4"><h4 class="legalArticleHeader" data-text-align="center"><span class="legalArticleValue">Article 4</span><br /><span class="legalArticleTitle">Results of sampling and analysis</span></h4><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="1" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-4-nummer-1">1. Each consignment of food referred to in Article 1(1) shall be accompanied by the results of sampling and analysis performed by the competent authorities of the country of origin as referred to in Annex I or of the third country where the consignment is consigned from if that country is different from the country of origin, to ascertain compliance with Union legislation on maximum residue levels of pesticides.<ul class="defaultList"><li data-li-identifier="2." data-name="2."><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-4-nummer-1-punkt-1"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-4-nummer-1-punkt-1-ledd-1">The sampling referred to in paragraph 1 must be performed in accordance with Directive 2002/63/EC.</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="3." data-name="3."><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-4-nummer-1-punkt-2"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-4-nummer-1-punkt-2-ledd-1">The analysis referred to in paragraph 1 must be performed by laboratories accredited in accordance with the standard ISO/IEC 17025 on ‘General requirements for the competence of testing and calibration laboratories’.</article></article></li></ul></article></article><article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/a5" data-name="a5" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-5"><h4 class="legalArticleHeader" data-text-align="center"><span class="legalArticleValue">Article 5</span><br /><span class="legalArticleTitle">Health certificate</span></h4><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="1" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-5-nummer-1">1. Each consignment of food referred to in Article 1(1) shall be accompanied by the original version of a health certificate, in accordance with the model set out in Annex II.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="2" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-5-nummer-2">2. The health certificate shall be completed, signed and verified by the competent authority of the country of origin or of the country where the consignment is consigned from if that country is different from the country of origin.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="3" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-5-nummer-3">3. The health certificate shall be drawn up in the official language, or in one of the official languages, of the Member State where the designated point of entry is located. However, a Member State may consent to health certificates being drawn up in another official language of the Union.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="4" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-5-nummer-4">4. The health certificate must be issued before the consignment to which it relates leaves the control of the competent authority issuing it.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="5" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-5-nummer-5">5. The health certificate shall only be valid during four months from the date of issue.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="6" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-5-nummer-6">6. The original health certificate shall be presented to, and kept by, the competent authorities of the designated point of entry.</article></article><article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/a6" data-name="a6" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-6"><h4 class="legalArticleHeader" data-text-align="center"><span class="legalArticleValue">Article 6</span><br /><span class="legalArticleTitle">Identification</span></h4><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-6-ledd-1">Each consignment of food referred to in Article 1(1) shall be identified with an identification code which corresponds to the identification code mentioned on the results of the sampling and analysis referred to in Article 4 and the health certificate referred to in Article 5. Each individual bag, or other packaging form, of the consignment shall be identified with that identification code.</article></article><article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/a7" data-name="a7" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-7"><h4 class="legalArticleHeader" data-text-align="center"><span class="legalArticleValue">Article 7</span><br /><span class="legalArticleTitle">Prior notification of consignments</span></h4><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="1" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-7-nummer-1">1. Food business operators or their representatives shall give prior notification of the estimated date and time of physical arrival of consignments of food referred to in Article 1(1) to the competent authorities at the designated point of entry and of the nature of the consignment.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="2" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-7-nummer-2">2. For the purpose of prior notification, food business operators or their representatives shall complete Part I of the common entry document (CED) and transmit that document to the competent authorities at the designated point of entry, at least one working day prior to the physical arrival of the consignment.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="3" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-7-nummer-3">3. For the completion of the CED pursuant to this Regulation, food business operators or their representatives shall take into account the notes for guidance for the CED laid down in Annex II to Regulation (EC) No 669/2009.</article></article><article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/a8" data-name="a8" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-8"><h4 class="legalArticleHeader" data-text-align="center"><span class="legalArticleValue">Article 8</span><br /><span class="legalArticleTitle">Official controls</span></h4><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="1" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-8-nummer-1">1. The competent authorities at the designated point of entry shall carry out documentary checks in relation to each consignment of food referred to in Article 1(1) to ascertain compliance with the requirements laid down in Articles 4 and 5.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="2" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-8-nummer-2">2. Member States shall carry out identity and physical checks on consignments, including sampling and analysis, in accordance with Articles 8(1), 9 and 19 of Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 at the frequency set out in Annex I to this Regulation.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="3" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-8-nummer-3">3. After completion of the checks, the competent authorities shall:<ul class="defaultList"><li data-li-identifier="(a)" data-name="(a)"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-8-nummer-3-punkt-1"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-8-nummer-3-punkt-1-ledd-1">complete the relevant entries of Part II of the CED;</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="(b)" data-name="(b)"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-8-nummer-3-punkt-2"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-8-nummer-3-punkt-2-ledd-1">join the results of sampling and analysis carried out in accordance with paragraph 2 of this Article to the CED;</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="(c)" data-name="(c)"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-8-nummer-3-punkt-3"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-8-nummer-3-punkt-3-ledd-1">provide and fill the CED reference number on the CED;</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="(d)" data-name="(d)"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-8-nummer-3-punkt-4"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-8-nummer-3-punkt-4-ledd-1">stamp and sign the original of the CED;</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="(e)" data-name="(e)"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-8-nummer-3-punkt-5"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-8-nummer-3-punkt-5-ledd-1">make and retain a copy of the signed and stamped CED.</article></article></li></ul></article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="4" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-8-nummer-4">4. The competent authorities of the designated point of entry shall issue the operator responsible for the consignment with an authenticated copy of the health certificate or, if the consignment is split, with individually authenticated copies of such certificate.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="5" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-8-nummer-5">5. The original of the CED shall accompany the consignment during its transport until it is released for free circulation.</article></article><article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/a9" data-name="a9" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-9"><h4 class="legalArticleHeader" data-text-align="center"><span class="legalArticleValue">Article 9</span><br /><span class="legalArticleTitle">Splitting of a consignment</span></h4><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="1" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-9-nummer-1">1. The consignment shall not be split until all official controls have been completed, and the CED has been fully completed by the competent authorities as provided for in Article 8.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="2" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-9-nummer-2">2. In the case of subsequent splitting of the consignment, an authenticated copy of the CED shall accompany each part of the consignment during its transport until it is released for free circulation.</article></article><article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/a10" data-name="a10" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-10"><h4 class="legalArticleHeader" data-text-align="center"><span class="legalArticleValue">Article 10</span><br /><span class="legalArticleTitle">Release for free circulation</span></h4><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-10-ledd-1">The release for free circulation of consignments shall be subject to the presentation by the food business operators or their representative to the custom authorities of a CED duly completed by the competent authority once all official controls have been carried out. The custom authorities shall only release the consignment for free circulation if a favourable decision by the competent authority is indicated in box II.14 of the CED and the CED is signed in box II.21 thereof.</article></article><article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/a11" data-name="a11" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-11"><h4 class="legalArticleHeader" data-text-align="center"><span class="legalArticleValue">Article 11</span><br /><span class="legalArticleTitle">Non-compliance</span></h4><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="1" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-11-nummer-1">1. Where the official controls carried out in accordance with Article 8 establish non-compliance with the relevant Union legislation, including this Regulation, the competent authority shall complete Part III of the CED and action shall be taken pursuant to Articles 19, 20 and 21 of Regulation (EC) No 882/2004.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="2" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-11-nummer-2">2. Where a consignment is not accompanied by both the results of sampling and analysis referred to in Article 4 and the health certificate referred to in Article 5 or if those results or that health certificate do not comply with the requirements laid down in this Regulation, the consignment shall not be imported into the Union and shall be redispatched outside the Union or destroyed.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="3" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-11-nummer-3">3. Where the competent authority at the designated point of entry does not permit the introduction of a consignment of food referred to in Article 1(1) due to non-compliance with a maximum residue level set out in Regulation (EC) No 396/2005, it shall immediately notify such border rejection in accordance with Article 19(3) of Regulation (EC) No 882/2004.</article></article><article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/a12" data-name="a12" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-12"><h4 class="legalArticleHeader" data-text-align="center"><span class="legalArticleValue">Article 12</span><br /><span class="legalArticleTitle">Reports</span></h4><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="1" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-12-nummer-1">1. Member States shall submit to the Commission biannually, by the end of the month following each semester, a report of all analytical results of official controls carried out on consignments of food pursuant to this Regulation.<article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-12-nummer-1-ledd-1">That report shall include the following information:<ul class="defaultList"><li data-li-identifier="(a)" data-name="(a)"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-12-nummer-1-ledd-1-punkt-1"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-12-nummer-1-ledd-1-punkt-1-ledd-1">the number of consignments imported;</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="(b)" data-name="(b)"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-12-nummer-1-ledd-1-punkt-2"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-12-nummer-1-ledd-1-punkt-2-ledd-1">the number of consignments subjected to sampling for analysis;</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="(c)" data-name="(c)"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-12-nummer-1-ledd-1-punkt-3"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-12-nummer-1-ledd-1-punkt-3-ledd-1">the results of the checks as provided for in Article 8(2).</article></article></li></ul></article></article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="2" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-12-nummer-2">2. The reporting obligations set out in paragraph 1 shall be deemed to be satisfied where Member States register in TRACES the CEDs issued by their respective competent authorities in accordance with this Regulation.</article></article><article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/a13" data-name="a13" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-13"><h4 class="legalArticleHeader" data-text-align="center"><span class="legalArticleValue">Article 13</span><br /><span class="legalArticleTitle">Review</span></h4><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-13-ledd-1">This Regulation shall be reviewed before 31 October 2019.</article></article><article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/a14" data-name="a14" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-14"><h4 class="legalArticleHeader" data-text-align="center"><span class="legalArticleValue">Article 14</span><br /><span class="legalArticleTitle">Costs</span></h4><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-14-ledd-1">All costs resulting from the official controls including sampling, analysis, storage and any measures taken following noncompliance shall be borne by the food business operators responsible for the consignment.</article></article><article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/a15" data-name="a15" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-15"><h4 class="legalArticleHeader" data-text-align="center"><span class="legalArticleValue">Article 15</span><br /><span class="legalArticleTitle">Amendment to Regulation (EC) No 669/2009</span></h4><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-15-ledd-1">Annex I to Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 is amended as follows:<ul class="defaultList"><li data-li-identifier="(a)" data-name="(a)"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-15-ledd-1-punkt-1"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-15-ledd-1-punkt-1-ledd-1">in the entries for Turkey, the entry referring to ‘Vine leaves’ is deleted.</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="(b)" data-name="(b)"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-15-ledd-1-punkt-2"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-15-ledd-1-punkt-2-ledd-1">in the entries for Vietnam, the entry referring to ‘Pitahaya (dragon fruit)’ is deleted.</article></article></li></ul></article></article><article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/a16" data-name="a16" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-16"><h4 class="legalArticleHeader" data-text-align="center"><span class="legalArticleValue">Article 16</span><br /><span class="legalArticleTitle">Repeal</span></h4><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-16-ledd-1">Implementing Regulation (EU) No 885/2014 is repealed.</article></article><article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/a17" data-name="a17" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-17"><h4 class="legalArticleHeader" data-text-align="center"><span class="legalArticleValue">Article 17</span><br /><span class="legalArticleTitle">Transitional measures</span></h4><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-17-ledd-1">For a period of three months from the date of entry into force of this Regulation, Member States shall continue to authorise the introduction of consignments of curry leaves originating from India which left the country of origin, or the country of consignment if that country is different from the country of origin, prior to 8 December 2018 provided that those consignments fulfil the requirements of Implementing Regulation (EU) No 885/2014.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-17-ledd-2">For a period of three months from the date of entry into force of this Regulation, Member States shall continue to authorise the introduction of consignments of vine leaves originating from Turkey and of Pitahaya (dragon fruit) originating from Vietnam which left the country of origin, or the country of consignment if that country is different from the country of origin, prior to 8 December 2018 provided that those consignments fulfil the requirements of Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 in force on 7 December 2018.</article></article><article class="legalArticle" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/a18" data-name="a18" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-18"><h4 class="legalArticleHeader" data-text-align="center"><span class="legalArticleValue">Article 18</span><br /><span class="legalArticleTitle">Entry into force and date of application</span></h4><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-18-ledd-1">This Regulation shall enter into force on the twentieth day following that of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Union.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-18-ledd-2">It shall apply from 8 December 2018.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-18-ledd-3">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-paragraf-18-ledd-4">Done at Brussels, 7 November 2018. <table><tbody><tr><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top" /><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top"><i>For the Commission</i></td></tr><tr><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top" /><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top" /></tr><tr><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top" /><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top"><i>The President</i></td></tr><tr><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top" /><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top" /></tr><tr><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top" /><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Jean-Claude JUNCKER</td></tr></tbody></table></article></article><section class="section" data-name="vedleggI" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-kapittel-1" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/KAPITTEL_4-1-1"><h4 data-text-align="center">Vedlegg I til forordning (EU) 2018/1660<br />Food of non-animal origin subject to special conditions regarding their import into the European Union:</h4><article class="defaultP"><table><thead><tr><th data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="middle"><i>Næringsmidler (tiltenkt bruk)</i></th><th data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="middle"><i>CN Code<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="1" data-unique-footnote-counter="1">1</sup></i></th><th data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="middle"><i>TARIC<br />–<br />inndeling<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="a" data-unique-footnote-counter="12">a</sup></i></th><th data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="middle"><i>Norsk varenummer</i></th><th data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="middle"><i>Opprinnelsesstat eller avsenderstat</i></th><th data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="middle"><i>Risiko</i></th><th data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="middle"><i>Hyppighet av fysiske kontroller og identitetskontroller (%)</i></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Pitahaya (dragefrukt)</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">ex 0810 90 20</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">10</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">ex 08.10.9090</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">Vietnam</td><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Rester av plantevernmidler listet opp i kontrollprogrammet gitt i medhold av artikkel 29(2) i forordning (EF) nr. 396/2005 (plantevernmidler som skal overvåkes i og på produkter av vegetabilsk opprinnelse)<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="2" data-unique-footnote-counter="2">2</sup> og rester av ditiokarbamater<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="3">3</sup> (ditiokarbamater uttrykt som CS2, inkludert maneb,<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="3">3</sup> mankozeb,<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="3">3</sup> metiram,<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="3">3</sup> propineb,<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="3">3</sup> tiram,<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="3">3</sup> ziram<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="3">3</sup> ) og fentoat<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="3">3</sup> og kvinalfos<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="3">3</sup></td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">10</td></tr><tr><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top"><i>(Næringsmidler – friske eller kjølte)</i></td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top" /><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top" /><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top" /><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top" /><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top" /><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top" /></tr><tr class="startGroup"><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Karriblader (<i>Bergera/Murraya koenigii</i>)</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">ex 1211 90 86</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">10</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">ex 12.11.9000</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">India</td><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Rester av plantevernmidler listet opp i kontrollprogrammet gitt i medhold av artikkel 29 (2) i forordning (EF) nr. 396/2005 (plantevernmidler som skal overvåkes i og på produkter av vegetabilsk opprinnelse)<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="2" data-unique-footnote-counter="2">2</sup> og rester av acefat<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="2" data-unique-footnote-counter="2">2</sup></td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">20</td></tr><tr><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top"><i>(Næringsmidler – urter – friske, tørkede og fryste)</i></td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top" /><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top" /><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top" /><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top" /><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top" /><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top" /></tr><tr class="startGroup"><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Vinblader</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">ex 2008 99 99</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">11; 19</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">ex 20.08.9909</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">Tyrkia</td><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Rester av plantevernmidler listet opp i kontrollprogrammet gitt i medhold av artikkel 29(2) i forordning (EF) nr. 396/2005 (plantevernmidler som skal overvåkes i og på produkter av vegetabilsk opprinnelse)<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="2" data-unique-footnote-counter="2">2</sup> og rester av ditiokarbamater<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="3">3</sup> (ditiokarbamater uttrykt som CS2, inkludert maneb,<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="3">3</sup> mankozeb,<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="3">3</sup> metiram,<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="3">3</sup> propineb,<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="3">3</sup> tiram,<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="3">3</sup> ziram<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="3">3</sup> ) og metrafenon<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="2" data-unique-footnote-counter="2">2</sup></td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">20</td></tr><tr><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top"><i>(Næringsmidler)</i></td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top" /><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top" /><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top" /><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top" /><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top" /><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top" /></tr></tbody></table></article><footer class="footnotes"><article class="footnote" data-name="1" data-unique-footnote-counter="9"><span class="footnoteLabel">1</span> Når bare visse produkter i en underposisjon skal undersøkes, og det ikke finnes noen særskilt varenummer i tolltariffen, står det «ex» foran underposisjonen.</article><article class="footnote" data-name="2" data-unique-footnote-counter="10"><span class="footnoteLabel">2</span> Plantevernmiddelrester analysert ved multirest-metoder basert på GC-MS og LC-MS.</article><article class="footnote" data-name="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="11"><span class="footnoteLabel">3</span> Plantevernmiddelrester analysert ved singelrest-metoder.</article><article class="footnote" data-name="a" data-unique-footnote-counter="12"><span class="footnoteLabel">a</span> TARIC er en nærmere inndeling av produktgrupper i tillegg til KN-koden. TARIC er en internt system for EU som er knyttet til tollområdet.</article></footer></section><section class="section" data-name="vedleggII" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-kapittel-2" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/KAPITTEL_4-1-2"><h4 data-text-align="center">Vedlegg II til forordning (EU) 2018/1660</h4><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-4-kapittel-1-kapittel-2-ledd-1">For helsesertifikatet for forordning (EU) 2018/1660 se pdf-filen nedenfor under avsnittet Forordninger i PDF.</article></section></section></section><section class="section" id="kapittel-5" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2018-11-19-1773/KAPITTEL_5"><h2>Forordninger i pdf</h2><article class="defaultP">Hele avsnittet om Forordning (EU) nr. 885/2014 (engelsk) slettes og erstattes av:</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Nedenfor gjengis forordning (EU) 2018/1660.</article><span class="futuretitle" id="kapittel-5-foreslåttittel-1">Forordning (EU) 2018/1660</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-5-ledd-1">For å lese forordning (EU) 2018/1660, med helsesertifikatet i vedlegg II, se her: (pdf)</article><article class="centeredP" data-text-align="center">II</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-5-ledd-2">I forskrift 22. desember 2008 nr. 1621 om offentlig kontroll med etterlevelse av regelverk om fôrvarer, næringsmidler og helse og velferd hos dyr (kontrollforskriften) gjøres følgende endringer i den konsoliderte versjonen av forordning (EF) nr. 669/2009:</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Innledningsteksten skal lyde:</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-5-ledd-3">Nedenfor gjengis til informasjon EØS-avtalen vedlegg I kapittel II nr. 47 og vedlegg II kapittel XII nr. 54zzzzo (forordning (EF) nr. 669/2009 som endret ved forordning (EU) nr. 212/2010, forordning (EU) nr. 878/2010, forordning (EU) nr. 1099/2010, forordning (EU) nr. 187/2011, forordning (EU) nr. 433/2011, forordning (EU) nr. 799/2011, forordning (EU) nr. 1277/2011 og forordning (EU) nr. 294/2012), vedlegg I kapittel I del 7.1 nr. 13, kap. II nr. 41 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) nr. 514/2012, forordning (EU) nr. 889/2012 og forordning (EU) nr. 1235/2012, forordning (EU) nr. 91/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 270/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 618/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 925/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 1355/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 323/2014, forordning (EU) nr. 718/2014, forordning (EU) nr. 1021/2014, forordning (EU) nr. 1295/2014, forordning (EU) 2015/525, forordning (EU) 2015/943, forordning (EU) 2015/1012, forordning (EU) 2015/1607, forordning (EU) 2015/2383, forordning (EU) 2016/24, forordning (EU) 2016/166, forordning (EU) 2016/443, forordning (EU) 2016/1024, forordning (EU) 2016/2107, forordning (EU) 2017/186, forordning (EU) 2017/1142, forordning (EU) 2017/2298, forordning (EU) 2018/941 og forordning (EU) 2018/1660) med de endringer og tillegg som følger av EØS-tilpasningen av rettsakten i samsvar med vedlegg I og II til EØS-avtalen.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-5-ledd-4">Forordning (EF) nr. 669/2009 er konsolidert til og med endringer gjennomført ved forordning (EU) 2018/1660.</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">I konsolideringsoversikten tilføyes følgende:</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">►<strong>M35</strong> Kommisjonens gjennomføringsforordning (EU) 2018/1660 av 7. november 2018</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">I vedlegg I skal følgende avsnitt slettes:<ul class="defaultList"><li data-li-identifier="-" data-name="-"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-5-ledd-4-punkt-1"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-5-ledd-4-punkt-1-ledd-1">avsnittet om vinblader fra Tyrkia</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="-" data-name="-"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-5-ledd-4-punkt-2"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-5-ledd-4-punkt-2-ledd-1">avsnittet om pitahaya (dragefrukt) fra Vietnam.</article></article></li></ul></article></section></main></body></html>