<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE html>
<html lang="no">
  <head>
    <title>Forskrift om endring i forskrift om s&#xE6;rlige tiltak mot Republikken Zimbabwe</title>
    <base href="https://lovdata.no/"/>
  </head>
  <body>
    <header class="documentHeader" id="hode">
      <dl class="data-document-key-info">
        <dt class="legacyID">Datokode</dt>
        <dd class="legacyID">FOR-2010-03-05-356</dd>
        <dt class="dokid">DokumentID</dt>
        <dd class="dokid">LTI/forskrift/2010-03-05-356</dd>
        <dt class="ministry">Departement</dt>
        <dd class="ministry">
          <ul>
            <li>Utenriksdepartementet</li>
          </ul>
        </dd>
        <dt class="publishedIn">Publisert i</dt>
        <dd class="publishedIn">I 2010 hefte 4 s 693</dd>
        <dt class="dateInForce">I kraft fra</dt>
        <dd class="dateInForce">2010-03-05</dd>
        <dt class="changesToDocuments">Endrer</dt>
        <dd class="changesToDocuments">
          <ul>
            <li>forskrift/2003-08-15-1050</li>
          </ul>
        </dd>
        <dt class="appliesTo">Gjelder for</dt>
        <dd class="appliesTo">Norge</dd>
        <dt class="basedOn">Hjemmel</dt>
        <dd class="basedOn">
          <ul>
            <li>forskrift/2003-08-15-1050/&#xA7;9</li>
            <li>lov/2003-06-27-58</li>
          </ul>
        </dd>
        <dt class="dateOfPublication">Kunngjort</dt>
        <dd class="dateOfPublication">2010-03-12 14:40</dd>
        <dt class="journalNumber">Journalnummer</dt>
        <dd class="journalNumber">2010-0221</dd>
        <dt class="titleShort">Korttittel</dt>
        <dd class="titleShort">Endr. i forskrift om s&#xE6;rlige tiltak mot Zimbabwe</dd>
        <dt class="title">Tittel</dt>
        <dd class="title">Forskrift om endring i forskrift om s&#xE6;rlige tiltak mot Republikken Zimbabwe</dd>
        <dt class="miscInformation">Annet om dokumentet</dt>
        <dd class="miscInformation"><strong>Hjemmel:</strong> Fastsatt av Utenriksdepartementet 5. mars 2010 med hjemmel i forskrift 15. august 2003 nr. 1050 om s&#xE6;rlige tiltak mot Republikken Zimbabwe &#xA7; 9, jf. lov 27. juni 2003 nr. 58 om s&#xE6;rlige tiltak mot Republikken Zimbabwe.</dd>
        <dt class="refid">RefID</dt>
        <dd class="refid">forskrift/2010-03-05-356</dd>
        <dt class="table-of-contents">Innhold</dt>
        <dd class="table-of-contents">
          <ul class="tocTopUl">
            <li>Forskrift om endring i forskrift om s&#xE6;rlige tiltak mot Republikken Zimbabwe<ul class="tocSubUl"><li>I</li><li>II</li></ul></li>
          </ul>
        </dd>
      </dl>
    </header>
    <main class="documentBody" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2010-03-05-356" id="dokument">
      <h1>Forskrift om endring i forskrift om s&#xE6;rlige tiltak mot Republikken Zimbabwe</h1>
      <section class="section" data-name="kapI" id="kapittel-1" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2010-03-05-356/KAPITTEL_1">
        <h2 data-text-align="center">I</h2>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-1">I forskrift 15. august 2003 nr. 1050 om s&#xE6;rlige tiltak mot Republikken Zimbabwe gj&#xF8;res f&#xF8;lgende endring:</article>
        <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Vedlegg II skal lyde:</article>
        <span class="futuretitle" id="kapittel-1-foresl&#xE5;ttittel-1">Vedlegg II: Liste med fysiske og juridiske personer, enheter og organer omhandlet i &#xA7; 7</span>
        <article class="defaultP">
          <table>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th colspan="2" data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">
                  <i>Fysiske personer</i>
                </th>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <th data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">
                  <i>Navn (etternavn, fornavn)</i>
                </th>
                <th data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">
                  <i>Identifiserende informasjon (stillingstittel, arbeidssted, f&#xF8;dselsdato, ektefellen til eller s&#xF8;nn/datter av mv.) og begrunnelse for listef&#xF8;ringen</i>
                </th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">1. Mugabe, Robert Gabriel</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">President, f&#xF8;dt 21.2.1924, Passnr. AD001095. Head of Government and as such responsible for activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">2. Abu Basutu, Titus MJ</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Air Vice-Marshal, Matebeleland South. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">4. Barwe, Reuben</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Journalist with Zimbabwe Broadcasting Corporation, f&#xF8;dt 19.3.1953, passnr.: BN311374. Whipped up the government-orchestrated terror campaign before and during the 2008 elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">5. Bonyongwe, Happyton</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Director-General Central Intelligence Organisation, f&#xF8;dt 6.11.1960, passnr.: AD002214 Ties to the Government and complicit in forming or directing repressive state policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">6. Bonyongwe, Willa (alias Willia)</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Chair of Securities Commission, married to Happyton Bonyongwe. Supporter and beneficiary of the regime through appointment and through close association with key member of the Government.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">7. Bredenkamp, John Arnold</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Businessman, f&#xF8;dt 11.08.1940, passnr.: Netherlands (1285143, expired), Zimbabwe (Z01024064, Z153612), Surinam (367537C). Businessman with strong ties to the Government of Zimbabwe. He has provided, including through his companies, financial and other support to the regime (see also items 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 12, 14, 20, 24, 25, 28, 29, 31 and 32 in part II).</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">8. Buka (alias Bhuka), Flora</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">President's office (Former Minister of State for Special Affairs responsible for Land and Resettlement Programmes, former Minister of State in the Vice-President's office and former Minister of State for the Land Reform in the President's Office), f&#xF8;dt 25.2.1968. Former member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">9. Bvudzijena, Wayne</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Assistant Police Commissioner, Police Spokesman. Member of the security forces and bearing wide responsibility for defending serious violations of human rights.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">10. Chairuka, Annie Flora Imagine</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Married to Paradzai Zimondi. Supporter and beneficiary of the regime through close association with key member of the Government.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">11. Chapfika, David</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Deputy Minister of Agriculture (former Deputy Minister of Finance), f&#xF8;dt 7.4.1957. Former member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">12. Charamba, George</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Permanent Secretary, Department for Information and Publicity, f&#xF8;dt 4.4.1963, passnr. AD002226. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">13. Charamba, Rudo Grace</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Married to George Charamba, f&#xF8;dt 20.6.1964. Supporter and beneficiary of the regime through close association with key member of the Government.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">14. Charumbira, Fortune Zefanaya</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Deputy Minister for Local Government, Public Works and National Housing, f&#xF8;dt 10.6.1962. Former member of the Government with ongoing ties.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">15. Chidarikire, Faber Edmund</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Provincial Governor for Mashonaland West, former Mayor of Chinhoyi, f&#xF8;dt 6.6.1946. Ties to the Government.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">16. Chigudu, Tinayes</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Provincial Governor: Manicaland. Ties to the Government and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of human rights.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">17. Chigwedere, Aeneas Soko</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Provincial Governor: Mashonaland East, f&#xF8;dt 25.11.1939. Former member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">18. Chihota, Phineas</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy Minister for Industry and International Trade. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">19. Chihuri, Augustine</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Police Commissioner, f&#xF8;dt 10.3.1953. Member of the security forces and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of the freedom of peaceful assembly.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">20. Chihuri, Isobel (alias Isabel) Halima</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Married to Augustine Chihuri, f&#xF8;dt 14.4.1974. Supporter and beneficiary of the regime through close association with key member of the Government.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">21. Chimbudzi, Alice</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU (PF) Politburo Committee Member. Member of the politburo and as such with strong ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">22. Chimedza, Paul</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">President of the medical Association of Zimbabwe, Dr, f&#xF8;dt 29.6.1967. Engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">23. Chimutengwende, Chenhamo Chekezha</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Minister of State for Public and Interactive Affairs (former Minister of Information, former Minister of Post and Telecommunications), f&#xF8;dt 28.8.1943. Former member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">24. Chinamasa, Monica</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">President of the Zimbabwe National Farmers Union, married to Patrick Chinamasa, f&#xF8;dt 1950. Supporter and beneficiary of the regime through close association with key member of the Government and implicated in activities that undermine the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">25. Chinamasa, Patrick Anthony</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Minister of Justice, Legal and Parliamentary Affairs, f&#xF8;dt 25.1.1947. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">26. Chindori-Chininga, Edward Takaruza</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Minister of Mines and Mining Development, f&#xF8;dt 14.3.1955. Former member of the Government with ongoing ties to the Government.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">27. Chingoka, Peter Farai</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Chairman of Zimbabwe Cricket, f&#xF8;dt 2.3.1954. Ties to the Government and implicated in activities that undermine the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">28. Chinotimba, Joseph</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Vice Chairman of the Zimbabwe National Liberation War Veterans Association, leader of ZANU-PF militia. Engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law, including direct involvement in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">29. Chipanga, Tongesai Shadreck</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Deputy Minister of Home Affairs, f&#xF8;dt 10.10.1940. Former member of the Government with ongoing ties to the Government.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">30. Chipwere, Augustine</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Colonel, Bindura South. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">31. Chiremba, Mirirai</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Director of Financial Intelligence at the Reserve Bank of Zimbabwe, f&#xF8;dt 14.5.1962. Ties to the Government and complicit in forming or directing repressive state policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">32. Chitakunye, Eliphas</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">High Court Justice. Has refused to allow investigation of abductions and torture at the hands of security agents.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">33. Chitepo, Victoria</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU-PF Politburo Committee Member (former Minister of Information, former Minister of Post and Telecommunications and former Tourism Minister.), f&#xF8;dt 27.3.1928. Member of the politburo and as such with strong ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">34. Chiwenga, Constantine</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Commander Zimbabwe Defence Forces, General (former Army Commander, Lieutenant General), f&#xF8;dt 25.8.1956. Member of the security forces and complicit in forming or directing repressive state policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">35. Chiwenga, Jocelyn</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Businesswoman, f&#xF8;dt 19.5.1955, married to General Chiwenga, Commander of the Defence Forces. Engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">36. Chiweshe, George</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Chairman, Zimbabwe Electoral Commission (Supreme Court Judge and Chairman of the controversial delimitation committee), f&#xF8;dt 4.6.1953. Ties to the Government and complicit in forming or directing repressive state policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">37. Chiwewe, Willard</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Provincial Governor: Masvingo (former Senior Secretary responsible for Special Affairs in the President's Office), f&#xF8;dt 19.3.1949. Former member of the Government with ongoing ties and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of human rights.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">38. Chombo, Ignatius Morgan Chiminya</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Minister of Local Government, Public Works and Urban Development, f&#xF8;dt 1.8.1952. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">40. Damasane, Abigail</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy Minister for Women's Affairs, Gender and Community Development. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">41. Deketeke, Pikirayi</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Chair of Broadcasting Authority of Zimbabwe and Editor of the official pro-government newspaper &#xAB;The Herald&#xBB;. Ties to the Government and implicated in activities that seriously undermine freedom of expression and the media.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">42. Dinha, Martin</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Provincial Governor for Mashonaland Central. Ties to the Government.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">43. Dokora, Lazarus</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy Minister for Higher and Tertiary Education, f&#xF8;dt 3.11.1957. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">44. Dube, Tshinga Judge</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Head of Zimbabwe Defence Industries and ZANU-PF candidate in the parliamentary elections, Retired Colonel, f&#xF8;dt 3.7.1941. Ties to the Government and complicit in forming or directing repressive state policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">45. Gambe, Theophilus</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Chairman, Electoral Supervisory Commission. Shares responsibility for fraudulent elections in 2005.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">46. Georgias, Aguy</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy Minister for Economic Development, f&#xF8;dt 22.6.1935. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">47. Goche, Nicholas Tasunungurwa</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Minister of Public Service, Labour and Social Welfare (former Minister of State for National Security in the President's Office), f&#xF8;dt 1.8.1946. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">48. Gono, Gideon</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Governor of the Reserve Bank of Zimbabwe (central bank), f&#xF8;dt 29.11.1959. Ties to the Government and complicit in forming or directing repressive state policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">49. Goyo, Helen (alias Hellin) Mushanyuri</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Married to Gideon Gono, f&#xF8;dt 6.5.1962. Supporter and beneficiary of the regime through close association with key member of the Government.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">50. Gula-Ndebele, Sobuza</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Attorney-General (Former Chairman of Electoral Supervisory Commission). Ties to the Government and complicit in forming or directing repressive state policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">51. Gumbo, Rugare Eleck Ngidi</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Minister of Agriculture (Former Minister of Economic Development), f&#xF8;dt 8.3.1940. Former member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">52. Gurira, Cephas T.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Colonel, Mhondoro Mubaira. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">53. Gwekwerere, Stephen</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Colonel, Chinhoyi. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">55. Hungwe, Josaya (alias Josiah) Dunira</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Provincial Governor: Masvingo, f&#xF8;dt 7.11.1935. Ties to the Government and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of human rights.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">56. Huni, Munyaradzi</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Journalist on the official pro-government newspaper &#xAB;The Herald&#xBB;, f&#xF8;dt 24.7.1973, passnr.: BN160327. Whipped up the terror campaign before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">58. Kachepa, Newton</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Member of Parliament elect for Mudzi North. Directly involved in the campaign of terror waged before and after the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">59. Kangai, Kumbirai</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU-PF Politburo Committee Member, f&#xF8;dt 17.2.1938. Member of the politburo and as such with strong ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">60. Karakadzai, Mike Tichafa</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Air Commodore, Harare Metropolitan Province. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">61. Karimanzira, David Ishemunyoro Godi</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Provincial Governor: Harare and ZANU-PF Politburo Secretary for Finance, f&#xF8;dt 25.5.1947. Ties to the Government and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of human rights.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">62. Kasukuwere, Saviour</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy Minister for Youth Development &amp; Employment Creation and ZANU-PF Politburo Deputy-Secretary for Youth Affairs, f&#xF8;dt 23.10.1970. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">63. Kaukonde, Ray Joseph</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Provincial Governor: Mashonaland East, f&#xF8;dt 4.3.1963.Ties to the Government and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of human rights.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">64. Kazangarare, Jawet</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU-PF Councillor in Hurungwe North and war veteran. Directly involved in the government-orchestrated terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">65. Kazembe, Joyce Laetitia</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy Chairperson of the Zimbabwe Electoral Commission and Chair of ZEC's Media Monitoring Commission. Shares responsibility for the fraudulent election process in 2008.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">66. Kereke, Munyaradzi</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Chief Adviser to the Governor of the Reserve Bank of Zimbabwe, f&#xF8;dt 29.7.1972. Ties to the Government and complicit in forming or directing repressive state policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">67. Khumalo, Sibangumuzi</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Brigadier General, Matebeleland North. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">68. Kunonga, Nolbert (alias Nobert)</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Self-appointed Anglican Bishop. Vociferous supporter of the regime. His followers have been backed by the police in committing acts of violence.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">69. Kuruneri, Christopher Tichaona</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Minister of Finance and Economic Development, f&#xF8;dt 4.4.1949. NB currently in remand. Former member of the Government with ongoing ties.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">70. Kwainona, Martin</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Assistant Commissioner. Directly involved in the campaign of terror waged before and after the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">71. Kwenda, R.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Major, Zaka East. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">72. Langa, Andrew</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy Minister of Environment and Tourism (former Deputy Minister of Transport and Communications). Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">73. Lesabe, Thenjiwe V.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU-PF Politburo Committee Member, f&#xF8;dt 1933. Member of the politburo and as such with strong ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">74. Mabunda, Musarashana</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Assistant Police Commissioner. Member of the security forces and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of the freedom of peaceful assembly.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">75. Machaya, Jason (alias Jaison) Max Kokerai</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Provincial Governor: Midlands. Former Deputy Minister of Mines and Mining Development, f&#xF8;dt 13.6.1952. Former member of the Government with ongoing ties.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">76. Made, Joseph Mtakwese</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">State Minister of Agricultural Engineering and Mechanisation (Former Minister of Agriculture and Rural Development), f&#xF8;dt 21.11.1954. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">77. Made, Patricia A.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former director of Inter-Press Service, married to Joseph Made. Supporter and beneficiary of the regime through close association with key member of the Government and implicated in activities that have undermined freedom of expression and the media.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">78. Madzongwe, Edna (alias Edina)</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU-PF President of Senate, f&#xF8;dt 11.7.1943. Member of the politburo and as such with strong ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">79. Mahofa, Shuvai Ben</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Deputy Minister for Youth Development, Gender and Employment Creation, f&#xF8;dt 4.4.1941. Former member of the Government with ongoing ties.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">80. Mahoso, Tafataona</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Chair, Media Information Commission. Ties to the Government and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of the freedom of expression and media.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">81. Makwanya, Judith</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Journalist with Zimbabwe Broadcasting Corporation, f&#xF8;dt 22.10.1963. Whipped up the government-orchestrated terror campaign before and during the 2008 elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">82. Makwavarara, Sekesai</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Mayor of Harare. Ties to the Government and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of human rights.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">83. Malinga, Joshua</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU-PF Politburo Deputy Secretary for Disabled and Disadvantaged, f&#xF8;dt 28.4.1944. Member of the politburo and as such with strong ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">84. Maluleke, Titus</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Provincial Governor: Masvingo (Former Deputy Minister of Education, Sports and Culture). Former Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">85. Mangwana, Paul Munyaradzi</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Minister of State for Indigenisation and Empowerment, f&#xF8;dt 10.8.1961. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">86. Manyonda, Kenneth Vhundukai</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Deputy Minister of Industry and International Trade, f&#xF8;dt 10.8.1934. Former member of the Government with ongoing ties.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">87. Marumahoko, Reuben</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy Minister for Foreign Affairs (former Deputy Minister for Home Affairs), f&#xF8;dt 4.4.1948. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">88. Masawi, Ephrahim Sango</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Provincial Governor: Mashonaland Central. Ties to the Government and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of human rights.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">89. Mashava, G.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Colonel, Chiredzi Central. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">90. Masuku, Angeline</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Provincial Governor: Matabeleland South and ZANU-PF Politburo, Secretary for Disabled and Disadvantaged, f&#xF8;dt 14.10.1936. Ties to the Government and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of human rights.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">91. Matanyaire, Munyaradzi</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Chief Executive Officer of Zimbabwe Inter-Africa News Agency. Ties to the Government and implicated in activities that seriously undermine freedom of expression and the media.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">92. Mathema, Cain Ginyilitshe Ndabazekhaya</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Provincial Governor: Bulawayo. Ties to the Government and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of human rights.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">93. Mathuthu, Thokozile</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Provincial Governor: Matabeleland North and ZANU-PF Politburo, Deputy Secretary for Transport and Social Welfare. Ties to the Government and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of human rights.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">94. Matiza, Joel Biggie</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy Minister for Rural Housing and Social Amenities, f&#xF8;dt 17.8.1960. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">95. Matonga, Brighton</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy Minister for Information and Publicity, f&#xF8;dt 1969. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">96. Matshalaga, Obert</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy Minister of Home Affairs (Former Deputy Minister of Foreign Affairs), f&#xF8;dt 21.4.1951 in Mhute Kraal &#x2013; Zvishavane. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">97. Matshiya, Melusi (Mike)</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Permanent Secretary, Ministry of Home Affairs. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">98. Mavhaire, Dzikamai</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU-PF Politburo Committee Member. Member of the politburo and as such with strong ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">99. Mbiriri, Partson</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Permanent Secretary, Ministry of Local Government, Public Works and Urban Development. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">100. Mhandu, Cairo (alias Kairo)</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Major Zimbabwe National Army. Directly involved in the campaign of terror waged before and after the elections</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">101. Mhonda, Fidellis</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Colonel, Rushinga. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">102. Midzi, Amos Bernard (Mugenva)</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Minister of Mines and Mining Development (former Minister of Energy and Power Development), f&#xF8;dt 4.7.1952.Former member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">103. Mnangagwa, Emmerson Dambudzo</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Minister of Rural Housing and Social Amenities (former Speaker of Parliament), f&#xF8;dt 15.9.1946. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">104. Mohadi, Kembo Campbell Dugishi</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Minister of Home Affairs (former Deputy Minister of Local Government, Public Works and National Housing), f&#xF8;dt 15.11.1949. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">105. Mombeshora, Millicent Sibongile</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Head of Strategic Planning and Special Projects, Reserve Bank of Zimbabwe, f&#xF8;dt 8.7.1965, Passnr.: BN177069. Ties to the Government and complicit in forming or directing repressive state policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">106. Moyo, Gilbert</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">&#xAB;War veteran&#xBB;, leader of ZANU-PF militia. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections in Mashonaland West (Chegutu).</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">107. Moyo, Jonathan</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Minister of State for Information and Publicity in the President's Office, f&#xF8;dt 12.1.1957. Former member of the Government engaged in activities that seriously undermined fundamental freedoms.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">108. Moyo, July Gabarari</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Minister of Energy and Power Development (former Minister of Public Service, Labour and Social Welfare), f&#xF8;dt 7.5.1950. Former member of the Government with ongoing ties.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">109. Moyo, Sibusio Bussie</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Brigadier General Zimbabwe National Army. Directly involved in the campaign of terror waged before and after the elections</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">110. Moyo, Simon Khaya</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Ambassador to South Africa and ZANU-PF Politburo Deputy Secretary for Legal Affairs, f&#xF8;dt 1945. Member of the politburo with ongoing ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">111. Mpabanga, S.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Lieutenant-Colonel, Mwenezi East Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">112. Mpofu, Obert Moses</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Minister for Industry and International Trade (former Provincial Governor: Matabeleland North) (ZANU-PF Politburo Deputy Secretary for National Security), f&#xF8;dt 12.10.1951. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">114. Msipa, Cephas George</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Provincial Governor: Midlands, f&#xF8;dt 7.7.1931. Ties to the Government and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of human rights.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">115. Muchechetere, Happison</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Acting Chief Executive of Zimbabwe Broadcasting Corporation. Ties to the Government and implicated in activities that seriously undermine freedom of expression and the media.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">116. Muchena, Henry</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Air Vice-Marshal, Midlands. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">117. Muchena, Olivia Nyembesi (alias Nyembezi)</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Minister of State for Science and Technology in the President's Office (former Minister of State in Vice-President Msika's Office), f&#xF8;dt 18.8.1946. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">118. Muchinguri, Oppah Chamu Zvipange</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU-PF Politburo Secretary for Gender and Culture (Former Minister for Women's Affairs, Gender and Community Development), f&#xF8;dt 14.12.1958. Former member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">119. Muchono, C.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Lieutenant-Colonel, Mwenezi West. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">120. Mudede, Tobaiwa (alias Tonneth)</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Registrar General, f&#xF8;dt 22.12.1942. Ties to the Government and complicit in forming or directing state policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">121. Mudenge, Isack Stanislaus Gorerazvo</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Minister of Higher Tertiary Education (former Minister of Foreign Affairs), f&#xF8;dt 17.12.1941. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">122. Mudonhi, Columbus</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Assistant Inspector Zimbabwe National Army. Directly involved in the campaign of terror waged before and after the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">123. Mudzvova, Paul</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Sergeant. Directly involved in the campaign of terror waged before and after the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">124. Mugabe, Grace</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">F&#xF8;dt 23.7.1965, Passnr.: AD001159. Spouse of the Head of Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">125. Mugabe, Leo</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Director of Zimbabwe Defence Industries, f&#xF8;dt (a) 28.8.1962; (b) 28.2.1957. Businessman with strong ties to the Government of Zimbabwe, and nephew of Robert Mugabe.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">126. Mugabe, Sabina</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU-PF Politburo Senior Committee Member, f&#xF8;dt 14.10.1934. Member of the politburo and as such with strong ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">127. Mugariri, Bothwell</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Senior Assistant Police Commissioner. Former member of the security forces and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of the freedom of peaceful assembly.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">128. Muguti, Edwin</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy Minister for Health and Child Welfare, f&#xF8;dt 1965. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">129. Mujuru, Joyce Teurai Ropa</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Vice President (former Minister of Water Resources and Infrastructural Development), f&#xF8;dt 15.4.1955. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">130. Mujuru, Solomon T.R.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU-PF Politburo Senior Committee Member, f&#xF8;dt 1.5.1949. Member of the politburo and as such with strong ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">131. Mukosi, Musoro Wegomo</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Producer with Zimbabwe Broadcasting Corporation. Whipped up the government-orchestrated terror campaign before and during the 2008 elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">132. Mumba, Isaac</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Superintendent. Directly involved in the campaign of terror waged before and after the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">133. Mumbengegwi, Samuel Creighton</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Minister of Finance; former Minister of State for Indigenisation and Empowerment, f&#xF8;dt 23.10.1942. Former member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">134. Mumbengegwi, Simbarashe Simbanenduku</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Minister of Foreign Affairs, f&#xF8;dt 20.7.1945, passnr.: AD001086. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">135. Murerwa, Herbert Muchemwa</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Minister of Finance, f&#xF8;dt 31.7.1941. Former member of the Government with ongoing ties.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">136. Musariri, Munyaradzi</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Assistant Police Commissioner. Member of the security forces and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of the freedom of peaceful assembly.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">137. Mushohwe, Christopher Chindoti</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Provincial Governor: Manicaland. (Former Minister of Transport and Communications, former Deputy Minister of Transport and Communications), f&#xF8;dt 6.2.1954. Former member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">138. Mutasa, Didymus Noel Edwin</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Minister of State for National Security, Land Reform and Resettlement in the Office of the President, ZANU-PF, Secretary for Administration, f&#xF8;dt 27.7.1935. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">139. Mutasa, Gertrude</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Colonel in the Zimbabwe Defence Force, married to Didymus Mutasa. Involved in farm invasions where death threats were made.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">140. Mutasa, Justin Mutsawehuni</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Chair of Zimbabwe Broadcasting Holdings and Chief Executive of Zimbabwe Newspapers, f&#xF8;dt 6.4.1954, passnr.: BN498951. Ties to the Government and involved in activities that seriously undermine freedom of expression and the media.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">141. Mutezo, Munacho</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Minister for Water Resources and Infrastructural Development.Former member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">142. Mutinhiri, Ambros (alias Ambrose)</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Minister of Youth Development, Gender and Employment Creation, Retired Brigadier. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">143. Mutinhiri, Tracey</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy Minister for Indigenisation and Empowerment (Former Deputy Speaker of the Senate). Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">144. Mutiwekuziva, Kenneth Kaparadza</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Deputy Minister of Small and Medium Enterprises, Development and Employment Creation, f&#xF8;dt 27.5.1948. Former member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">145. Mutsvunguma, S.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Colonel, Headlands. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">146. Muzenda, Tsitsi V.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU-PF Politburo Senior Committee Member, f&#xF8;dt 28.10.1922. Member of the politburo and as such with strong ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">147. Muzonzini, Elisha</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Brigadier (former Director-General Central Intelligence Organisation), f&#xF8;dt 24.6.1957. Former member of the security forces and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of the freedom of peaceful assembly.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">148. Mzembi, Walter</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy Minister for Water Resources and Infrastructural Development, f&#xF8;dt 16.3.1964. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">149. Mzilikazi, Morgan S.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Colonel (MID), Buhera Central. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">150. Ncube, Abedinico</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy Minister of Public Service, Labour and Social Welfare (former Deputy Minister of Foreign Affairs), f&#xF8;dt 13.10.1954. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">151. Ndlovu, Naison K.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy President of the Senate, and ZANU-PF Politburo Secretary for Production and Labour, f&#xF8;dt 22.10.1930. Member of the politburo and as such with strong ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">152. Ndlovu, Richard</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU-PF Politburo Deputy Commissariat, f&#xF8;dt 26.6.1942. Member of the politburo and as such with strong ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">153. Ndlovu, Sikhanyiso</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Minister of Information and Publicity (Former Deputy Minister of Higher and Tertiary Education), f&#xF8;dt 20.9.1949. Former member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">154. Nguni, Sylvester</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Minister of Economic Development (Former Deputy Minister for Agriculture), f&#xF8;dt 4.8.1955. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">155. Nhema, Francis</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Minister of Environment and Tourism, f&#xF8;dt 7.4.1959. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">156. Nkala, Herbert</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Chair of Zimbabwe Newspapers, which prints State propaganda and Chair of First Banking Corporation.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">157. Nkomo, John Landa</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Speaker of House of Assembly (former Minister of Special Affairs in the President's Office), ZANU-PF national chairman, f&#xF8;dt 22.8.1934. Former member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">158. Nyambuya, Michael Reuben</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Minister for Energy and Power Development (former Lieutenant General, Provincial Governor: Manicaland), f&#xF8;dt 23.7.1955. Former member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">159. Nyanhongo, Magadzire Hubert</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy Minister of Transport and Communications. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">160. Nyathi, George</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU-PF Politburo Deputy Secretary of Science and Technology. Member of the politburo and as such with strong ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">161. Nyawani, Misheck</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Retired Superintendent. Directly involved in the campaign of terror waged before and after the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">162. Nyikayaramba, Douglas</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Brigadier General, Mashonaland East. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">163. Nyoni, Sithembiso Gile Glad</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Minister of Small and Medium Enterprises Development and Employment Creation, f&#xF8;dt 20.9.1949. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">164. Parirenyatwa, Choice</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Married to David Parirenyatwa. Supporter and beneficiary of the regime through close association with key member of the Government.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">165. Parirenyatwa, David Pagwese</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Minister of Health and Child Welfare (former Deputy Minister), f&#xF8;dt 2.8.1950. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">166. Patel, Bharat</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Acting Attorney General, Justice, Hon. Engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">167. Patel, Khantibhal</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU-PF Politburo Deputy Secretary for Finance, f&#xF8;dt 28.10.1928. Member of the politburo and as such with strong ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">168. Pote, Selina M.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU-PF Politburo Deputy Secretary for Gender and Culture. Member of the politburo and as such with strong ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">169. Rangwani, Dani</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Police Detective Inspector. Member of the security forces and engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">170. Rautenbach, Muller Conrad (alias Billy)</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Businessman, f&#xF8;dt. 23.9.1959, PO Box CH52, Chisipite, Harare, passnr.: BN491589. Businessman with strong ties to the Government of Zimbabwe, including through support to senior regime officials during Zimbabwe's intervention in DRC (see also item 26 in part II).</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">171. Rugeje, Engelbert Abel</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Major-General, Masvingo Province. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">172. Rungani, Victor TC</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Colonel, Chikomba. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">173. Ruwodo, Richard</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Brigadier General, promoted on 12 August 2008 to the rank of Major General (retired); former Acting Permanent Under Secretary (PUS) for Ministry of Defence, f&#xF8;dt 14.3.1954. Directly involved in the campaign of terror waged before and after the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">174. Sakabuya, Morris</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy Minister for Local Government, Public Works and Urban Development. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">175. Sakupwanya, Stanley</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU-PF Politburo Deputy Secretary for Health and Child Welfare. Member of the politburo and as such with strong ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">176. Samkange, Nelson Tapera Crispen</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Provincial Governor: Mashonaland West. Ties to the Government and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of human rights.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">177. Sandi, E.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU-PF Politburo Deputy Secretary for Women's Affairs. Member of the politburo and as such with strong ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">178. Savanhu, Tendai</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU-PF Deputy Secretary for Transport and Social Welfare, f&#xF8;dt 21.3.1968. Member of the politburo and as such with strong ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">179. Sekeramayi, Sydney (alias Sidney) Tigere</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Minister of Defence, f&#xF8;dt 30.3.1944. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">180. Sekeremayi (alias Sekeramayi), Tsitsi Chihuri</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Married to Sydney Sekeremayi, f&#xF8;dt 1944. Supporter and beneficiary of the regime through close association with key member of the Government.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">181. Sekeremayi, Lovemore</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Chief Elections Officer. Ties to the Government and complicit in forming or directing oppressive state policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">182. Shamu, Webster Kotiwani</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Minister of State for Policy Implementation (former Minister of State for Policy Implementation in the President's Office), f&#xF8;dt 6.6.1945. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">183. Shamuyarira, Nathan Marwirakuwa</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU-PF Politburo Secretary for Information and Publicity, f&#xF8;dt 29.9.1928. Member of the politburo and as such with strong ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">184. Shiri, Perence (alias Bigboy Samson Chikerema)</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Air Marshal (Air Force), f&#xF8;dt 1.11.1955. Member of the security forces and complicit in forming or directing oppressive state policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">185. Shumba, Isaiah Masvayamwando</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy Minister of Education, Sports and Culture, f&#xF8;dt 3.1.1949. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">186. Shungu, Etherton</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Brigadier General, Mashonaland Central. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">187. Sibanda, Chris</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Colonel, Bulawayo Province. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">188. Sibanda, Jabulani</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Former Chair, National War Veterans Association, f&#xF8;dt 31.12.1970. Ties to the Government and complicit in forming or directing oppressive state policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">189. Sibanda, Misheck Julius Mpande</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Cabinet Secretary (successor to Charles Utete), f&#xF8;dt 3.5.1949. Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">190. Sibanda, Phillip Valerio (alias Valentine)</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Commander Zimbabwe National Army, Lieutenant General, f&#xF8;dt 25.8.1956. Member of the security forces and complicit in forming or directing oppressive state policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">191. Sigauke, David</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Brigadier General, Mash West Province. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">192. Sikosana, Absolom</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">ZANU-PF Politburo Secretary for Youth Affairs. Member of the politburo and as such with strong ties to the Government and its policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">193. Stamps, Timothy</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Health Adviser in the Office of the President, Former Health Minister, f&#xF8;dt 15.10.1936. Ties to the Government and complicit in forming or directing oppressive state policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">194. Tarumbwa, Nathaniel Charles</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Brigadier General, Manicaland and Mutare South. Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">195. Tomana, Johannes</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Attorney General. Engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">196. Tonderai Matibiri, Innocent</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy Police Commissioner. Member of the security forces and engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">197. Udenge, Samuel</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Minister of State for State Enterprises (Former Deputy Minister of Economic Development). Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">198. Utete, Charles</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Chairman of the Presidential Land Review Committee (former Cabinet Secretary), f&#xF8;dt 30.10.1938. Ties to the Government and complicit in forming or directing oppressive state policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">199. Veterai, Edmore</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Senior Assistant Police Commissioner, Officer Commanding Harare. Member of the security forces and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of the freedom of peaceful assembly.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">200. Zhuwao, Patrick</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Deputy Minister for Science and Technology (NB Mugabe's nephew). Member of the Government and as such engaged in activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">201. Zimondi, Paradzai</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Prisons Director, f&#xF8;dt 4.3.1947. Member of the security forces and complicit in forming or directing oppressive state policy.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">202. Zvayi, Caesar</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Journalist on the official pro-government newspaper &#xAB;The Herald&#xBB;. Whipped up the terror campaign before and during the elections.</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <table>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th colspan="2" data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">
                  <i>Juridiske personer, enheter og organer</i>
                </th>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <th data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">
                  <i>Navn</i>
                </th>
                <th data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">
                  <i>Identifiserende informasjon og begrunnelse for listef&#xF8;ringen</i>
                </th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">1. Alpha International (PVT) Ltd.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Park Road, Camberley, Surrey GU15 2SP, UK. Owned by John Arnold Bredenkamp.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">2. Breco (Asia Pacific) Ltd.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Isle of Man Company Registration M78647 &#x2013; 1st Floor, Falcon Cliff, Palace Road, Douglas IM2 4LB, Isle of Man. Owned by John Arnold Bredenkamp</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">3. Breco (Eastern Europe) Ltd.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Isle of Man Company Registration FC0021189 &#x2013; Falcon Cliff, Palace Road, Douglas IM99 1ZW, Isle of Man; Hurst, Reading Berkshire RG10 0SQ, UK. Owned by John Arnold Bredenkamp.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">4. Breco (South Africa) Ltd.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Isle of Man Company Registration Q1962 &#x2013; Cumbrae House, Market Street, Douglas IM1 2PQ, Isle of Man; 9 Columbus Centre, Pelican Drive, Road Town, Tortola, British Virgin Islands. Owned by John Arnold Bredenkamp.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">5. Breco (UK) Ltd.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">UK Company Registration 2969104 &#x2013; London Road, Sunningdale, Ascot, Berkshire SL5 0DJ, UK. Owned by John Arnold Bredenkamp.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">6. Breco Group</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Thetford Farm, PO Box HP86, Mount Pleasant, Harare, Zimbabwe; Sandford Lane, Hurst, Reading, Berks RG10 0SQ, UK; London Road, Sunningdale, Ascot, Berks, SL5 0DJ, UK. Owned by John Arnold Bredenkamp.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">7. Breco International 25</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Broad Street, St. Helier JE2 3RR, Jersey. Owned by John Arnold Bredenkamp.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">8. Breco Nominees Ltd. UK</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Company Registration 2799499 &#x2013; London Road, Sunningdale, Ascot, Berkshire SL5 0DJ, UK. Owned by John Arnold Bredenkamp.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">9. Breco Services Ltd. UK</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Company Registration 2824946 &#x2013; London Road, Sunningdale, Ascot, Berkshire SL5 0DJ, UK. Owned by John Arnold Bredenkamp.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">10. Cold Comfort Farm Trust Co-operative</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">7 Cowie Road, Tynwald, Harare, Zimbabwe. Owned by Didymus Mutasa, Grace Mugabe also involved.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">11. Comoil (PVT) Ltd.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Block D, Emerald Hill Office, Emerald Park, Harare, Zimbabwe. 2nd Floor, Travel Plaza, 29 Mazoe Street, Box CY22344 Causeway, Harare, Zimbabwe. Owned by Saviour Kasukuwere.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">12. Corybantes Ltd.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">London Road, Sunningdale, Ascot, Berkshire SL5 0DJ, UK; Titlarks Hill Road, Sunningdale, Ascot, Berkshire, SL5 0JB, UK. Owned by John Arnold Bredenkamp.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">13. Divine Homes (PVT) Ltd.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">6 Hillside Shopping Centre, Harare, Zimbabwe; 31 Kensington Highlands, Harare, Zimbabwe; 12 Meredith Drive, Eastlea, Harare, Zimbabwe. Chaired by David Chapfika.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">14. Echo Delta Holdings</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Thetford Farm, PO Box HP86, Mount Pleasant, Harare, Zimbabwe; Sandford Lane, Hurst, Reading, Berks RG10 0SQ, UK; London Road, Sunningdale, Ascot, Berks, SL5 0DJ, UK. Owned by John Arnold Bredenkamp.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">15. Famba Safaris</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">4 Wayhill Lane, Umwisdale, Harare, Zimbabwe; PO Box CH273, Chisipite, Harare, Zimbabwe. Major shareholder is Webster Shamu.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">18. Jongwe Printing and Publishing Company (PVT) Ltd. (alias Jongwe Printing and Publishing Co., alias Jongwe Printing and Publishing Company)</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">14 Austin Road, Coventry Road, Workington, PO Box 5988, Harare, Zimbabwe. ZANU-PF's publishing arm.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">19. M &amp; S Syndicate (PVT) Ltd.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">First Floor, Victory House, 88 Robert Mugabe Road, Harare, Zimbabwe; PO Box 1275, Harare, Zimbabwe. ZANU-PF's investment company.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">20. Masters International Ltd.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">UK Company Registration 2927685 &#x2013; London Road, Sunningdale, Ascot, Berkshire SL5 0DJ, UK. Owned by John Arnold Bredenkamp.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">21. Ndlovu Motorways.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Sam Nujoma Street, Livingston Avenue, Harare, Zimbabwe Controlled by Sikhanyiso Ndlovu.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">23. OSLEG Ltd. (alias Operation Sovereign Legitimacy)</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Lonhoro House, Union Avenue, Harare, Zimbabwe. Controlled by Zimbabwe army.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">24. Piedmont (UK) Ltd.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">London Road, Sunningdale, Ascot, Berkshire SL5 0DJ, UK. Owned by John Arnold Bredenkamp.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">25. Raceview Enterprises</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Zimbabwe. Owned by John Arnold Bredenkamp.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">26. Ridgepoint Overseas Developments Ltd. (alias Ridgepoint Overseas Developments Ltd)</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">C/o: Mossack Fonseca &amp; Co BVI Ltd, Akara Building, 24. DeCastro St, Road Town, Tortola, British Virgin Islands; P.O. Box 3136, Road Town, Tortola, British Virgin Islands. Owned by Billy Rautenbach.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">28. Scottlee Holdings (PVT) Ltd.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">124 Josiah Chinamano Avenue, PO Box CY3371, Causeway, Harare, Zimbabwe; London Road, Sunningdale, Berkshire SL50DJ, UK. Owned by John Arnold Bredenkamp.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">29. Scottlee Resorts Ltd.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">124 Josiah Chinamano Avenue, PO Box CY3371, Causeway, Harare, Zimbabwe; London Road, Sunningdale, Berkshire SL50DJ, UK. Owned by John Arnold Bredenkamp.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">30. Swift Investments (PVT) Ltd.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">730 Cowie Road, Tynwald, Harare, Zimbabwe; PO Box 3928,Harare, Zimbabwe. Controlled by Zanu-PF, directors include Vitalis Zvinavashe.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">31. Timpani Export Ltd.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Isle of Man Company Registration 3547414 &#x2013; Falcon Cliff, Newton Abbot, Devon TQ12 2LG, UK; Mapstone Hill, Palace Road, Douglas IM99 1ZW, Isle of Man; King Street, Lustleigh, Newton Abbot, Devon TQ13 9SE, UK. Owned by John Arnold Bredenkamp.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">32. Tremalt Ltd.</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Thetford Farm, PO Box HP86, Mount Pleasant, Harare, Zimbabwe; Hurst Grove, Hurst, Reading, Berks RG10 0SQ, UK; London Road, Sunningdale, Ascot, Berks, SL5 0DJ, UK. Owned by John Arnold Bredenkamp.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">35. Zidco Holdings (alias Zidco Holdings (PVT) Ltd)</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">PO Box 1275, Harare, Zimbabwe. ZANU-PF's financial holding company.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">36. Zimbabwe Defence Industries</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">10th floor, Trustee House, 55 Samora Machel Avenue, PO Box6597, Harare, Zimbabwe. Wholly owned by the Government of Zimbabwe. Directors include Leo Mugabe and Solomon Mujuru.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">38. Zimbabwe Mining Development Corporation</td>
                <td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">90 Mutare Road, PO Box 2628, Harare, Zimbabwe. Wholly owned by the Government of Zimbabwe.</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
        </article>
      </section>
      <section class="section" data-name="kapII" id="kapittel-2" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2010-03-05-356/KAPITTEL_2">
        <h2 data-text-align="center">II</h2>
        <article class="legalP" id="kapittel-2-ledd-1">Endringen trer i kraft straks.</article>
      </section>
    </main>
  </body>
</html>
