<!DOCTYPE html><html lang="no"><head><title>Forskrift om endring i forskrift om særlige importbetingelser for fôrvarer og næringsmidler med opprinnelse i eller eksportert fra Japan</title><base href="https://lovdata.no/" /></head><body><header class="documentHeader" id="hode"><dl class="data-document-key-info"><dt class="legacyID">Datokode</dt><dd class="legacyID">FOR-2011-09-28-970</dd><dt class="dokid">DokumentID</dt><dd class="dokid">LTI/forskrift/2011-09-28-970</dd><dt class="ministry">Departement</dt><dd class="ministry"><ul><li>Fiskeridepartementet</li><li>Landbruks- og matdepartementet</li><li>Helse- og omsorgsdepartementet</li></ul></dd><dt class="publishedIn">Publisert i</dt><dd class="publishedIn">I 2011 hefte 9 s 1258</dd><dt class="dateInForce">I kraft fra</dt><dd class="dateInForce">2011-10-01</dd><dt class="changesToDocuments">Endrer</dt><dd class="changesToDocuments"><ul><li>forskrift/2011-03-30-338</li></ul></dd><dt class="appliesTo">Gjelder for</dt><dd class="appliesTo">Norge</dd><dt class="basedOn">Hjemmel</dt><dd class="basedOn"><ul><li>lov/2003-12-19-124/§16</li><li>lov/2003-12-19-124/§17</li><li>lov/2003-12-19-124/§23</li></ul></dd><dt class="dateOfPublication">Kunngjort</dt><dd class="dateOfPublication">2011-09-30 14:35</dd><dt class="journalNumber">Journalnummer</dt><dd class="journalNumber">2011-0741</dd><dt class="titleShort">Korttittel</dt><dd class="titleShort">Endr. i forskrift om import av varer fra Japan</dd><dt class="title">Tittel</dt><dd class="title">Forskrift om endring i forskrift om særlige importbetingelser for fôrvarer og næringsmidler med opprinnelse i eller eksportert fra Japan</dd><dt class="miscInformation">Annet om dokumentet</dt><dd class="miscInformation"><strong>Hjemmel:</strong> Fastsatt av Mattilsynet 28. september 2011 med hjemmel i lov 19. desember 2003 nr. 124 om matproduksjon og mattrygghet mv. (matloven) § 23 tredje ledd, jf. § 16 og § 17. <br /><strong>EØS-henvisninger:</strong> EØS-avtalen vedlegg I kap. I del 7.1 nr. 13, kap. II nr. 41 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) nr. 961/2011).</dd><dt class="refid">RefID</dt><dd class="refid">forskrift/2011-09-28-970</dd><dt class="table-of-contents">Innhold</dt><dd class="table-of-contents"><ul class="tocTopUl"><li>Forskrift om endring i forskrift om særlige importbetingelser for fôrvarer og næringsmidler med opprinnelse i eller eksportert fra Japan<ul class="tocSubUl"><li>I</li><li>II</li><li>Forordninger</li></ul></li></ul></dd></dl></header><main class="documentBody" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2011-09-28-970" id="dokument"><h1>Forskrift om endring i forskrift om særlige importbetingelser for fôrvarer og næringsmidler med opprinnelse i eller eksportert fra Japan</h1><section class="section" data-name="kapI" id="kapittel-1" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2011-09-28-970/KAPITTEL_1"><h2 data-text-align="center">I</h2><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-1">I forskrift 30. mars 2011 nr. 338 om særlige importbetingelser for fôrvarer og næringsmidler med opprinnelse i eller eksportert fra Japan gjøres følgende endringer:</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">EØS-henvisningsfeltet skal lyde:</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">EØS-henvisninger: EØS-avtalen vedlegg I kap. I del 7.1 nr. 13, kap. II nr. 41 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) nr. 961/2011).</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Tittel på § 2 skal lyde:</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true"><i>Forordning (EU) nr. 961/2011</i></article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">§ 2 skal lyde:</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-2">EØS-avtalens vedlegg I kapittel I del 7.1 nr. 13, kap. II nr. 41 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) nr. 961/2011) om særlige importbetingelser for fôrvarer og næringsmidler med opprinnelse i eller sendt fra Japan etter ulykken ved atomkraftverket i Fukushima og opphever forordning (EU) nr. 297/2011 gjelder som forskrift med de tilpasninger som følger av vedlegg I og II, protokoll 1 til avtalen og avtalen for øvrig.</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">§ 3 annet ledd skal lyde:</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-1-ledd-3">Mattilsynets enheter for veterinær grensekontroll ved Oslo lufthavn Gardermoen, Oslo havn og Borg havn utpekes som importsteder for ikke-animalske næringsmidler og fôrvarer fra Japan i henhold til forordning (EU) nr. 961/2011 artikkel 2.</article></section><section class="section" data-name="kapII" id="kapittel-2" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2011-09-28-970/KAPITTEL_2"><h2 data-text-align="center">II</h2><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-2-ledd-1">Denne forskriften trer i kraft 1. oktober 2011.</article></section><section class="section" id="kapittel-3" data-lovdata-URL="LTI/forskrift/2011-09-28-970/KAPITTEL_3"><h2>Forordninger</h2><article class="defaultP">Avsnittet Forordninger skal lyde:</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-ledd-1">Nedenfor gjengis forordning (EU) nr. 691/2011 som hjelpetekst. Erklæringen nevnt i artikkel 2 (5) finnes under vedlegg I i pdf-filen nedenfor. Grenseverdiene gitt i vedlegg II er gjengitt nedenfor på norsk.</article><span class="futuretitle" id="kapittel-3-foreslåttittel-1">Forordning (EU) nr. 961/2011 (engelsk)</span><article class="centeredP" data-text-align="center">COMMISSION IMPLEMENTING REGULATION (EU) No 961/2011</article><article class="centeredP" data-text-align="center">of 27 September 2011</article><article class="centeredP" data-text-align="center">imposing special conditions governing the import of feed and food originating in or consigned from Japan following the accident at the Fukushima nuclear power station and repealing Regulation (EU) No 297/2011</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">THE EUROPEAN COMMISSION,</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-ledd-2">Having regard to the Treaty on the Functioning of the European Union,</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-ledd-3">Having regard to Regulation (EC) No 178/2002 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 28 January 2002 laying down the general principles and requirements of food law, establishing the European Food Safety Authority and laying down procedures in matters of food safety,<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="1" data-unique-footnote-counter="1">1</sup> and in particular Article 53 (1) (b) (ii) thereof,</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">Whereas:</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="1" id="kapittel-3-nummer-1">(1) Article 53 of Regulation (EC) No 178/2002 provides for the possibility to adopt appropriate Union emergency measures for food and feed imported from a third country in order to protect public health, animal health or the environment, where the risk cannot be contained satisfactorily by means of measures taken by the Member States individually.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="2" id="kapittel-3-nummer-2">(2) Following the accident at the Fukushima nuclear power station on 11 March 2011, the Commission was informed that radionuclide levels in certain food products originating in Japan such as milk and spinach exceeded the action levels in food applicable in Japan. Such contamination may constitute a threat to public and animal health in the Union and therefore Commission Implementing Regulation (EU) No 297/2011 imposing special conditions governing the import of feed and food originating in or consigned from Japan following the accident at the Fukushima nuclear power station<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="2" data-unique-footnote-counter="2">2</sup> was adopted.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="3" id="kapittel-3-nummer-3">(3) Regulation (EU) No 297/2011 has been amended at several occasions to take into account the development of the situation. These amendments concerned the adoption of maximum levels of radioactivity to be applied for feed and food originating from Japan, addition of prefectures to the zone for which specific restrictions apply after contamination in these prefectures was found at levels above the maximum levels and removing prefectures from the zone with restrictions in case extensive monitoring has provided evidence that these prefectures were not affected to a significant extent by radioactive contamination.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="4" id="kapittel-3-nummer-4">(4) Since mid July 2011, the Commission was informed by the Japanese authorities of findings of high levels of caesium in beef from cattle grown in different prefectures in Japan. As the import of beef from Japan into the EU is not allowed for animal and public health reasons other than radioactivity, these findings do not affect the European consumer. Also recently, new food products have been found to contain levels of radioactivity above the maximum levels. These findings and the fact that new/other agricultural/horticultural crops are grown and harvested in the contaminated zone provide evidence that it is appropriate to maintain the current measures after 30 September 2011. It is therefore appropriate to continue to implement the present Regulation until 31 December 2011, instead of 30 September 2011 as initially foreseen. The principle of a monthly review of the implementation of the Regulation is maintained.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="5" id="kapittel-3-nummer-5">(5) Given that Regulation (EU) No 297/2011 has been amended several times in a short period of time it is appropriate to replace Regulation (EU) No 297/2011 by a new Regulation.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="6" id="kapittel-3-nummer-6">(6) The measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on the Food Chain and Animal Health,</article><footer class="footnotes"><article class="footnote" data-name="1" data-unique-footnote-counter="1"><span class="footnoteLabel">1</span> OJ L 31, 1.2.2002, p. 1.</article><article class="footnote" data-name="2" data-unique-footnote-counter="2"><span class="footnoteLabel">2</span> OJ L 80, 26.3.2011, p. 5.</article></footer> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</article><span class="futuretitle" id="kapittel-3-foreslåttittel-2">Article 1<br />Scope</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-ledd-4">This Regulation shall apply to feedstuffs and foodstuffs within the meaning of Article 1 (2) of Regulation (Euratom) No 3954/87<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="1" data-unique-footnote-counter="1">1</sup> originating in or consigned from Japan, with the exclusion of products which left Japan before 28 March 2011 and of products which have been harvested and/or processed before 11 March 2011.</article><footer class="footnotes"><article class="footnote" data-name="1" data-unique-footnote-counter="3"><span class="footnoteLabel">1</span> OJ L 371, 30.12.1987, p. 11.</article></footer><span class="futuretitle" id="kapittel-3-foreslåttittel-3">Article 2<br />Attestation</span><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="1" id="kapittel-3-nummer-7">1. All consignments of products referred to in Article 1 shall be subject to the conditions laid down in this Regulation.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="2" id="kapittel-3-nummer-8">2. Consignments of products referred to in Article 1 falling outside the scope of Council Directive 97/78/EC of 18 December 1997 laying down the principles governing the organisation of veterinary checks on products entering the Community for third countries<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="1" data-unique-footnote-counter="1">1</sup> shall be introduced into the Union through a designated point of entry within the meaning of Article 3 (b) of Commission Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 (hereinafter «designated point of entry»).<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="2" data-unique-footnote-counter="2">2</sup></article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="3" id="kapittel-3-nummer-9">3. Each consignment of products referred to in Article 1 shall be accompanied by a declaration, attesting that:<ul class="defaultList"><li data-li-identifier="(a)" data-name="(a)"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-3-nummer-9-punkt-1"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-nummer-9-punkt-1-ledd-1">the product has been harvested and/or processed before 11 March 2011, or</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="(b)" data-name="(b)"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-3-nummer-9-punkt-2"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-nummer-9-punkt-2-ledd-1">the product originates in and is consigned from a prefecture other than Fukushima, Gunma, Ibaraki, Tochigi, Miyagi, Nagano, Yamanashi, Saitama, Tokyo, Chiba, Kanagawa and Shizuoka, or</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="(c)" data-name="(c)"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-3-nummer-9-punkt-3"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-nummer-9-punkt-3-ledd-1">the product is consigned from Fukushima, Gunma, Ibaraki, Tochigi, Miyagi, Nagano, Yamanashi, Saitama, Tokyo, Chiba, Kanagawa and Shizuoka prefectures, but does not originate in one of those prefectures and has not been exposed to radioactivity during transiting, or</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="(d)" data-name="(d)"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-3-nummer-9-punkt-4"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-nummer-9-punkt-4-ledd-1">where a product originates in Fukushima, Gunma, Ibaraki, Tochigi, Miyagi, Nagano, Yamanashi, Saitama, Tokyo, Chiba, Kanagawa and Shizuoka prefectures, the product does not contain levels of radionuclides iodine-131, caesium-134 and caesium-137 above the maximum levels provided for in Annex II to this Regulation.</article></article></li></ul></article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="4" id="kapittel-3-nummer-10">4. Point (d) of paragraph 3 shall apply also to products caught or harvested in the coastal waters of the prefectures referred to therein, irrespective of where such products are landed.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="5" id="kapittel-3-nummer-11">5. The declaration referred to in paragraph 3 shall be drawn up in accordance with the model set out in Annex I. It shall be signed by an authorised representative of the competent authority of Japan. For the products referred to in point (d) of paragraph 3, the declaration shall be accompanied by an analytical report containing the results of sampling and analysis.</article><footer class="footnotes"><article class="footnote" data-name="1" data-unique-footnote-counter="4"><span class="footnoteLabel">1</span> OJ L 24, 30.1.1998, p. 9.</article><article class="footnote" data-name="2" data-unique-footnote-counter="5"><span class="footnoteLabel">2</span> OJ L 194, 25.7.2009, p. 11.</article></footer><span class="futuretitle" id="kapittel-3-foreslåttittel-4">Article 3<br />Identification</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-ledd-5">Each consignment of the products referred to in Article 1 shall be identified by means of a code which shall be indicated on the declaration referred to in Article 2 (3), on the analytical report referred to in Article 2 (5), on the sanitary certificate and on any commercial documents accompanying the consignment.</article><span class="futuretitle" id="kapittel-3-foreslåttittel-5">Article 4<br />Prior notification</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-ledd-6">Feed and food business operators or their representatives shall give prior notification of the arrival of each consignment of the products referred to in Article 1, at least two working days prior to the physical arrival of the consignment, to the competent authorities at the Border Inspection Post or at the designated point of entry.</article><span class="futuretitle" id="kapittel-3-foreslåttittel-6">Article 5<br />Official controls</span><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="1" id="kapittel-3-nummer-12">1. The competent authorities of the border inspection post or designated point of entry shall carry out:<ul class="defaultList"><li data-li-identifier="(a)" data-name="(a)"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-3-nummer-12-punkt-1"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-nummer-12-punkt-1-ledd-1">documentary and identity checks on all consignments of products referred to in Article 1, and</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="(b)" data-name="(b)"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-3-nummer-12-punkt-2"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-nummer-12-punkt-2-ledd-1">physical checks, including laboratory analysis on the presence of iodine-131, caesium-134 and caesium-137, on at least: <ul class="defaultList"><li data-li-identifier="-" data-name="-"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-3-nummer-12-punkt-2-ledd-1-punkt-1"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-nummer-12-punkt-2-ledd-1-punkt-1-ledd-1">10 % of the consignments of products referred to in Article 2 (3) (d) and</article></article></li><li data-li-identifier="-" data-name="-"><article class="listArticle" id="kapittel-3-nummer-12-punkt-2-ledd-1-punkt-2"><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-nummer-12-punkt-2-ledd-1-punkt-2-ledd-1">20 % of the consignments of products referred to in Article 2 (3) (b) and (c).</article></article></li></ul></article></article></li></ul></article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="2" id="kapittel-3-nummer-13">2. Consignments shall be kept under official control, for a maximum of 5 working days, pending the availability of the results of the laboratory analysis.</article><article class="numberedLegalP" data-numerator="3" id="kapittel-3-nummer-14">3. The release for free circulation of consignments shall be subject to the presentation by the feed and food business operator or its representative to the customs authorities of the declaration referred to Article 2 (3), duly endorsed by the competent authority at the border inspection post or designated point of entry, giving evidence that the official controls referred to in paragraph 1 have been carried out and that the results from physical checks, where such checks were carried out, have been favourable.</article><span class="futuretitle" id="kapittel-3-foreslåttittel-7">Article 6<br />Costs</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-ledd-7">All costs resulting from the official controls referred to in Article 5(1) and 5(2) and any measures taken following non-compliance, shall be borne by the feed and food business operator.</article><span class="futuretitle" id="kapittel-3-foreslåttittel-8">Article 7<br />Non-compliant products</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-ledd-8">Feed and food originating in or consigned from Japan which do not comply with the maximum levels referred to in Annex II shall not be placed on the market. Such non-compliant feed and food shall be safely disposed of or returned to the country of origin.</article><span class="futuretitle" id="kapittel-3-foreslåttittel-9">Article 8<br />Reports</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-ledd-9">Member States shall inform the Commission monthly through the Rapid Alert System for Food and Feed (RASFF) and the European Union's Urgent Radiological Information Exchange system (ECURIE) of all analytical results obtained.</article><span class="futuretitle" id="kapittel-3-foreslåttittel-10">Article 9<br />Repeal</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-ledd-10">Regulation (EU) No 297/2011 is repealed.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-ledd-11">References to the repealed Regulation shall be construed as references to this Regulation.</article><span class="futuretitle" id="kapittel-3-foreslåttittel-11">Article 10<br />Entry into force and period of application</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-ledd-12">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following that of its publication in the <i>Official Journal of the European Union</i>.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-ledd-13">It shall apply from the date of entry into force until 31 December 2011. The Regulation will be reviewed monthly taking into account the development of the contamination situation.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-ledd-14">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-ledd-15">Done at Brussels, 27 September 2011.</article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true"><i>For the Commission</i><p class="leddfortsettelse"><i>The President</i></p><p class="leddfortsettelse">José Manuel BARROSO</p></article><span class="futuretitle" id="kapittel-3-foreslåttittel-12">Vedlegg I til forordning (EU) nr. 961/2011</span><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-ledd-16">Se pdf-filen nedenfor.</article><span class="futuretitle" id="kapittel-3-foreslåttittel-13">Vedlegg II til forordning (EU) nr. 961/2011</span> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true"><i>Maksimalt tillatte nivåer for næringsmidler (Bq/kg):</i><sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="1" data-unique-footnote-counter="1">1</sup><table><thead><tr><th data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top" /><th data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top"><i>Næringsmidler for spedbarn og småbarn</i></th><th data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top"><i>Melk og meieriprodukter</i></th><th data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top"><i>Andre næringsmidler, utenom flytende næringsmidler</i></th><th data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top"><i>Flytende næringsmidler</i></th><th data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top" /></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Summen av strontium-isotoper, særlig Sr-90</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">75</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">125</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">750</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">125</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top" /></tr><tr><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Summen av jod-isotoper, særlig I-131</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">100</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">300</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">2 000</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">300</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top" /></tr><tr><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Summen av alfaaktive plutonium- og transplutonium-isotoper, særlig Pu-239 og Am-241</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">1</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">1</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">10</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">1</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top" /></tr><tr><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Summen av alle andre nuklider med en halveringstid på mer enn 10 dager, særlig Cs-134 og Cs-137, unntatt C-14 og H-3</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">200</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">200</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">500</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">200</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top" /></tr></tbody></table></article> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true"><i>Maksimalt tillatte nivåer for fôrvarer (Bq/kg):</i><sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="2" data-unique-footnote-counter="2">2</sup><table><thead><tr><th data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top" /><th data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top"><i>Fôr</i></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Summen av Cs-134 og Cs-137</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">500</td></tr><tr><td data-text-align="left" data-vertical-align="top">Summen av isotoper av jod, særlig I-131</td><td data-text-align="center" data-vertical-align="top">2&#xa0;000<sup class="footnotereference" data-footnotereferencevalue="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="8">3</sup></td></tr></tbody></table></article><footer class="footnotes"><article class="footnote" data-name="1" data-unique-footnote-counter="6"><span class="footnoteLabel">1</span> Nivået som skal anvendes for konsentrerte eller tørkede produkter skal beregnes på grunnlag av det rekonstituerte forbruksklare produktet.</article><article class="footnote" data-name="2" data-unique-footnote-counter="7"><span class="footnoteLabel">2</span> Grenseverdien gjelder fôr med et vanninnhold på 12&#xa0;%.</article><article class="footnote" data-name="3" data-unique-footnote-counter="8"><span class="footnoteLabel">3</span> Grenseverdien er fastsatt på midlertidig basis og er den samme som for næringsmidler, i vente på en vurdering av faktorene for overføring av jod fra fôrvarer til næringsmidler.</article></footer><span class="futuretitle" id="kapittel-3-foreslåttittel-14">Forordninger i pdf</span> <article class="defaultP" margin-top="true"><i>Forordning (EU) nr. 961/2011</i></article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-ledd-17">For å lese forordning (EU) nr. 961/2011 på dansk se her: (pdf)</article><article class="legalP" id="kapittel-3-ledd-18">For å lese forordning (EU) nr. 961/2011 på engelsk se her: (pdf)</article></section></main></body></html>